<dialogs><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Bona feina *kumpains* 😁</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Un dia qualsevol, entro al Reddit i veig una desmesurada activitat inusual a /r/Catalunya.

I així és com mhe assabentat daixò de la iniciativa /r/place. :D 

I com a mínim hem activat una mica el subreddit:
http://imgur.com/a/8RffZ</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Felicitats als que heu revertit els danys de la nit (club penguin i avatar). 

Hauríem hagut dacabar atacant factorio, no tenien perquè tenir dues zones (laltra està just sota la trobada entre Noruega i Suècia, i inclou tota la sanefa gris amb fletxes i els erlenmeyer). http://i.imgur.com/EZJsdqC.png</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Podem seguir aqui: http://pxls.space/</utt><utt uid="1">organitzemnos doncs! tot i aixo no hi ha masa activitat </utt><utt uid="0">La web no funciona gaire bé, però la gent ja ha començat a dibuixar coses. Algú vol contribuir? [Localització: (0,500)](http://easycaptures.com/fs/uploaded/993/0067426682.png)</utt><utt uid="1">No sera vostra la mitga bandera comunista amb mistages tipo ACAB (que tots sabem que vol dir all cats are beautifull) XD</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ueeeeee Catalina rises again!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ha quedat prasiós!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">una imatge per la posteritat :3</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Doncs no cal perquè ja està! Sha acabat /r/place
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona feina gent!!!!!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Enhorabona!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Faltaba el escudo del FC Barcelona 😭</utt><utt uid="1">Si :( haurem de muntar una aliança la pròxima vegada (si nhi ha, sisplau que nhi hagi). </utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">As a german from Bavaria, I would like to also express my support and solidarity with the Catalan people and their cause for democratic self-determination.

I really hope that at some point our government will put pressure on the Madrid government because obviously Germany is a major player in Europe.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Im actually bringing a Scottish flag to the demostration! Alongside with an Irish one. Love from your brother nation, Catalonia ♥</utt><utt uid="1">Wonderful! Hope it all goes well!</utt><utt uid="1">Hey, I saw an Irish flag... maybe it was you? I also saw Estonia!</utt><utt uid="0">Maybe! I had an Estelada, Irish and Scottish flag on the same thing.</utt><utt uid="1">Were you by any chance near [els gegants del Guinardó](https://i.imgur.com/DppKbHh.jpg)?</utt><utt uid="0">Not sure, I walked down almost all of the way into Plaça Catalunya :/</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Thank you very much 💚</utt><utt uid="1">You are quite welcome.  Have a great day and stay safe over these coming weeks.  The world is watching!</utt><utt uid="2">Super nice thxs!!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Such cute animals :)</utt><utt uid="1">Thank you, Im trying to create political cartoons that have a family friendly feel to them :)</utt><utt uid="0">Check out Pilarín Bayés, she has a style you might like and although few people know her by the name she has made herself a place in the Catalan collective imagery.</utt><utt uid="2">Oh wow, I didnt know her name, definitely seen her drawings many times though.</utt><utt uid="1">Thank you, Ill look her up :)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Thanks! Surprised to see someone from outside Catalonia cares. Good luck on your fight for independence too.</utt><utt uid="1">You’ve a lot of friends in Scotland :)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Gràcies! Thanks! Tapadh leat!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">What a nice picture! 😁, thanks!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Very appreciated :)</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Je suis un Québécois et je vous supporte. Ne lâchez pas! Avoir un pays est essentiel pour continuer à exister comme peuple! Courage mes amis!</utt><utt uid="1">So hows Canada working out for you?</utt><utt uid="2">Not great at all...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Vivre la Catalogne libre! Vive le Québec libre !</utt><utt uid="1">Catalonian independence will fail just like Quebec independence did.</utt><utt uid="0">I hope to prove you wrong sooner or later. </utt><utt uid="1">I hope so too, but from what we see, Spain will not allow it.</utt><utt uid="0">At some point they wont have the choice. The question is whether Catalunya will reach that point with their limited power. </utt><utt uid="2">How will they not have the choice? Which major foreign power is going to intervene, an act on par with declaring war on Spain? There are no heinous atrocities being committed against the Catalans, they enjoy a high standard of living and are free to sing and dance and eat and speak how they please. If you think the EU will intervene, youre blissfully unaware of the absolute prohibition Germany and France have on any seperatist movements. And 90% of the rest of Spain sees no reason for Catalonia disregard the Constitution. </utt><utt uid="2">This is not about spain allowing us but us applying the basic human right that all peoples have everywhere, the right to self-determination, the right to decide what you want to be</utt><utt uid="2">Would have failed 5 years ago if there had been a serious vote. Now Im not so sure.</utt><utt uid="2">The referendum can fail, but the movement and eventually independence wont fail.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Merci beacup! De Catalunya, nous apprécions vraiment ces gestes.</utt><utt uid="1">La lluita per la independència nacional sovint és una lluita sola. La solidaritat procedent dels països reconeguts és escassa (ara ho veiem els comentaris sobre r / worldnews o r / europe) ...
   
Crec que Quebeckers, escocesos, kurds i altres persones no reconegudes estan ben situades per entendre aquest aïllament i la dificultat daquests moments. És el més petit en aquest context per oferir-vos tot el nostre suport i per dir-vos que no hem de deixar anar.
  
La lutte dindépendance nationale est une lutte trop souvent seule. La solidarité venant de pays reconnus est rare (on le voit présentement par les commentaires sur r/worldnews ou r/europe)...  
   
Je crois que les Québécois, les Écossais, les Kurdes et tout autre peuple non-reconnu sont bien placés pour comprendre cet isolement et la difficulté de tels moments. Cest la moindre des choses dans ce contexte de vous offrir tout notre soutien et de vous dire, quil ne faut surtout pas lâcher.
  
Courage! Et bises du Québec.</utt><utt uid="2">Absolutely, I even think we catalans are used to be more alone than most even, because of the little awareness about our existance and struggles and the overt antypathy most spaniards show to our cause, which help swah uninformed obvservers</utt><utt uid="1">3 hope you will succeed and show us the path. </utt><utt uid="0">*Beaucoup.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">I dont take a position on whether or not Catalonia should be independent. But i think it should be up to you guys, and you should be able to make your own decision like we Scots were able to. Best of luck and I hope democracy prevails.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Merci! Nous apprécions vraiment que le Parti Québécois ait défendu publiquement le droit du peuple catalan à sexprimer en référendum et quil ait critiqué la façon dagir du gouvernement espagnol.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Self-determination for all peoples. Stay strong, Catalonia.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Merci!!!!!😁</utt><utt uid="1">3</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Thank you from Barcelona, with love 3</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Soon, all the traitors will be in front of the judges. Justice and democracy always prevails against the criminal and mentally ill. 

Spain 🇪🇸 will never be defeated. </utt><utt uid="1"> Spain 🇪🇸 will never be defeated. 

Not to be an ass, but a map of Spain thru history is like a Jenga game.

 Si jo lestiro fort per aquí i tu lestires fort per allà, 
segur que tomba, tomba, tomba, i ens podrem alliberar</utt><utt uid="0">Catalan kids know nothing. The educational system has been manipulated for decades with the sole purpose of creating citizens that hate their own motherland. 

No sir. Spain is the oldest nation in Europe. If you don’t believe read to Seneca. Hispania have thousands of years, literally. 
</utt><utt uid="1">Right, right, we evil catalans are indoctrinated people that hate spaniards so much, **we even plan to start eating your babies this October!**

Hispania≠Spain, but whateva!</utt><utt uid="2"> Catalan kids know nothing. The educational system has been manipulated for decades with the sole purpose of creating citizens that hate their own motherland.

May I suggest that catalan have heard both the catalan point of view and the spanish point of view for decades. In Catalunya, there are pro independence pro union, each side have a voice in this debate, on TV, in the newspapers, in cafés, etc. Catalans watch both catalan TV and spanish TV. They understand both catalan and spanish language.

May I suggest that spanish outside of Catalunya seldom hear the catalan independentist point of view and mainly the pro union spanish point of view.

May I then suggest that the youth who is brainwashed are not the one that you seem to think?</utt><utt uid="0">Education is everything and to brain wash little kids is something we don’t take lightly in the US. Right now, all we are seeing from outside is a shitshow where a few extremist want to break the law using any pretext at hand (which include a handful of lies)

I just hope that all the criminals are sent to prison soon, I have friends in Barcelona (Spain)
</utt><utt uid="3">Put them all in prison, but theyll vote, you cant stop it.</utt><utt uid="0">The government already stoped it as all the newspapers says. </utt><utt uid="3">Well snap! Youre right, its stopped - you can go away now, right? Since its stopped?

Itd be that much more relaxing not having to deal with you.</utt><utt uid="0">You have a very democratic attitude. It remains me of this whole situation... hmmm. 

I am so sorry for all the sane people that lives in that region of Spain. Brain washed sheeps like you have to be quite annoying to deal with. 

🇪🇸 kiss your flag. </utt><utt uid="3">Jokes on you, thats not my flag! I cant even vote. Just goes to show that Ive nothing to gain here and Im not brainwashed by the Catalan educational system like youd like people to believe.

Oh, and just to remind you in case you forgot, theyre going to vote!</utt><utt uid="3">Thats why Spain is shitting in its pants right?</utt><utt uid="0">If you say so... your ancestors got their ass wiped in the past and it will happen again if your force the situation. Speaking is all you know, let’s see what you do when the time comes and speaking is not enough </utt><utt uid="3">Are you going to kill Catalans? So democratic of you! 3</utt><utt uid="2">In India, the british put Gandhi and his followers in jail. When they had jailed 6,000 of them, the prisons were full and the justice system was ovewhelmed. The british were loosing the control of the situation, they then negociated with Gandhi.

6,000 out of a population of then 300 millions, and the all mighty british empire was brought to its knees.

What will the spanish do when they will run out of judges, of prisons cells, of policemen? How many traitors will they be able to arrest? 100? 1000? 10,000? I would add 100,000 but the number in itself is ridiculous?

Spain needs to collaboration of catalans. When the catalans will no longer collaborate, Spain will will lose effective control of the territory and Spain will no longer rule on Catalunya.

And yes democracy always prevails. I mean democracy as in allowing the people to vote...</utt><utt uid="0">It’s a nice fantasy. Good luck. </utt><utt uid="1">Democracy implies voting. But a voting doesnt mean democacry. Lots of totalitarian countries have elections. If you compare Ghandi and India with Catalonia and Puigdemont Im totally sure you havent gathered all the info. The issue is too serious.

I humble suggest you to search how this voting has been designed, by whom, its legal strucure and which population percentage they represent. And obviously, how Catalonia citizens live nowadays.

Create your own opinion free of romanticism and false victimism.

Dont let anyone, even me, to convice you so easily.
</utt><utt uid="2">It is true that lots of totalitarian countries have elections, but Catalunya is not a totalitarian country. In a situation where, on one side, catalonians want to vote on an issue and, on other side, a spanish government wants to prevent the people from voting by arresting and imprisoning elected leaders, I humbly suggest that democracy is on the side catalans.

Indias and Catalunyas situations are different, of course. But, to your comment suggesting that all traitors would be sent in front of the judge, I reminded that the former british colonial power in India tried too in its time to judge and jail, the traitors and that was beginning of the end of its rule over India. 

True, catalans have a high standard of living and perhaps this doesnt have as much to do with this as you believe.  </utt><utt uid="1">You can read this too 

http://www.ecfr.eu/amp-article/commentary_three_myths_about_catalonias_independence_movement

And remember that a voting without an agreement from all parts, enough, honest and clear info about the consequences, and respect for all the laws isnt a modern democratic exercise in any occidental country.</utt><utt uid="2">It is late at night now. I will read your article tomorrow, it seems interesting.

My understanding is that you live in the USA. Were you born there? Are you from Spain? from Catalunya? I was born and live in Québec, my native language is french.</utt><utt uid="1">I was born and raised in Spain. Ive been living long periods in Madrid and Valencia, now I live in Alicante where I was raised.

And I feel honored you think I could be from USA, because it means my English isnt as bad as I thought :).

In El Pais you can find english editorial versions, but most independentists hate that news source since it doesnt fit with their ideology.

https://elpais.com/elpais/inenglish.html

Their last editorial: https://elpais.com/elpais/2017/09/20/inenglish/1505917320_788824.html

I link you an editorial from Liberation (France) a source that no-one with common sense could tag as a nazi, ultra, or righ-wing biased.

http://www.liberation.fr/debats/2017/09/21/l-avenir-de-l-europe-se-joue-a-nouveau-en-catalogne_1597969

</utt><utt uid="2">I thought that you lived in the USA because you wrote : [...] something we don’t take lightly in the US. I assumed that it meant United States.

I read the Three Myths about Catalonia text. (I havent yet read El Pais.)

First, a note on style. I have found the accusations of racism and the use of expressions such as pet projects uselessly inflammatory. I have found amusing the downplaying of catalans grievances. Sure there were no Balkan style ethnic cleansing, but can one have grievances short of that? (And the catalan language was once forbidden and in a quebeckers eye, the forbiding of ones language is seen as the attempt to destroy a nation. One of our issues, I guess.)

More seriously, the author insist on a very legalistic approach as if the constitution was something sacred. (And wasnt this constitution supposed to be some sort of transition in the aftermaths of the Franco regime?) This constitution was not given to Spain by God, it has been adopted by the people in a referendum. What if someday the people changes its mind? What if one the peoples (one of the nations) changes its mind?

The problem is not a legal problem, it is a political problem and a referendum is a political solution. Let the people have its say. (Note 1)

The author insists, as you do I believe (note 2), that the independentists are only a minority. Very fine then, they will lose the referendum. But they might be a majority and they might win the referendum. And what would be wrong with that? This pro independence vote would be the will of the majority.


- - -
Note 1. You might argue that every spanish, catalans and non-catalans, should have their say because Catalunyas independence will impact whole Spain. True. But the decision of woman to leave her husband will impact the husbands life. Nevertheless, the husband cannot force her to stay, it is her decision to stay or to leave. A union requiers a mutual agreement.

Note 2. Interestingly, independentists, while being a tiny minority, are able to orchestrate the brainswashing of the know nothing masses and to manipulate brain washed sheeps into hat[ing] their own motherland.</utt><utt uid="1">You confused me with PeterTarantula. That has been a funny mistake, since for at least one day, I felt proud of my English... :)...

I agree that it isnt only a legal problem. But from spaniards point of view its difficult to understand their positions, almost impossible, to be honest.

And Catalonia has such a degree of automanagment that no central state institution is near the citizens: health, education, security, and many more have been Catalonian competences for decades, because they asked for those and central state gave them the responsability to attend those. 

One of the few central goberment competences is a big part of tax income managment, through central tax agency, and thats  another the reason Catalonians doesnt see with good eyes Spain. Tax agency can be seen as an unfriendly service, while most institutions which give services to catalonians (friendly services) are pure catalonian institutions. And when those doesnt work well they blame central state for not giving them enough money. As easy as that.

And if you add that education is in catalan language (spanish is second language, and is usually treated like a foreign language), and in most of their history text books  Catalonian history weights more than Spanish history, and all public Catalonian  TV and Radio only speak in Catalonian,... the disconnect feeling grew. That feeling has been used for independist blocs last ten years.

My personal point is clear. The referendum isnt legal and isnt clean enough. The independists crushed their own parlament rules those days (and spanish laws). There is no agreement and no clear info about consequences for such a serious voting. The catalonian leaders are using public institutions for their politic agenda, the disconnection process. The other side , the no side, has no real chance in such circunstances. ¿ what would happen to zones/cities which could vote no ? ¿ would those catalonians allowed to remain in Spain ? No. They wouldnt because their daft constitution of independence states, theyd become indivisible.

Look for editorials in other outlets: The Guardian, The Independent, ... to get more points of view.

Good luck!


</utt><utt uid="2">I confused you with PeterTarantula indeed, my mistake. And your english is just fine.

True, from from a spaniard (isnt the word spaniard suposed to be offensive?) point of view, its difficult to understand their positions, almost impossible. So is probably your point of view impossible to understand from their point of view. No surprise you are now on the verge of separation.

You gave me a link from Libération. Do you read/speak french? If so, you might be interested in this paper : http://www.journaldemontreal.com/2017/09/23/je-joue-cartes-sur-table-pour-vous

The author was born in Uruguay, first laguage is spanish, he has family in Spain and recently spent a year in Madrid to get back in touch with his relatives. He his also a political figure here (Québec) and a fervent Québec independentist. You might find his point of view interesting.

I only have a few minutes now. Just one more word to say that I do read about Catalunya from different sources, among them Radio-Canada vicioulsy opposed to Québec independence and usualy quite critical about any separatist movement (they will not fuel their own home grown separatists, you know...). </utt><utt uid="3">Youre right, and Spain is a prime example of a totalitarian state that has elections.</utt><utt uid="1">I do hope you never have to live in under a real totalitarian state.</utt><utt uid="3">Thanks for your fake sympathy, youre doing a wonderful service to your nation, showing how Spain is.</utt><utt uid="1">Thanks.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Molt agraït!!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">VVVVasc??? Mods</utt><utt uid="1">Grammar nazi!</utt><utt uid="2">País Valencià ;)</utt><utt uid="1">Fuck I didnt even notice that</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Gora Euskadi</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Nice.....</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Què penseu del moviment independentista del País Basc? És que, com nord-americà, el veig molt més difícil dalçar perquè el PB es troba enmig de dues nacions distintes. Dallí que, la gent hauria de convèncer tant als francesos com als espanyols que els hi deixin, oi?</utt><utt uid="1">Catalunya també la tenim dividida, encara que gran part del sentiment independentista de la catalunya nord el va aixafar frança ja fa molts anys, i mimagino que hauràn fet el mateix al pais basc, per tant el moviment basc deu ser més fort a la part espanyola que no pas a la francesa.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Basque≠ETA as Ku Klux Klan≠Christian. Its not that hard 😄</utt><utt uid="0">Your comments have been repeatedly on the line of what is considered acceptable. This comments is clearly a call to violence and its enjoyment, either from catalans or against catalans.

Your comment as been removed. I also ask you to get a better informed opinion before posting this kind comment of again, specially when it comes to calling someone responsible for the murder of thousands without clear knowledge of what you are talking about.

Youre not banned. This is only a warning.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Thank you to /u/raicopk for the translation assistance with this one :)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Big mistake by the spanish state. Arresting people and searching government buildings is whole new level and they cant derail the referendum this way.

We already know that there are over 700 mayors and 50,000 official organizers for the referendum. What are they going to do, arrest all of them? They would need prison camps if they try to round them all up, aside from the fact that each arrest would be paired with massive protests and they dont have the manpower to, for example, clear a street blocked by thousands of protestors sitting there.

It looks like Rajoy believes that he can really deny millions of determined people their right to self-determination.

I for one am really impressed by the determination of the people of Catalonia to take the streets and stand up for their rights in the face of repression. If you stand together, nobody can stop you.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">no ens deixarem aixafar</utt><utt uid="1">Stay strong, dont let them provoke you.  Resist, vote.</utt><utt uid="0">we will. we wont go back to a dictatorship state.</utt><utt uid="2">Wow, you actually believe that Spain is still a dictatorship! Statements like yours is what really scares me, and I fear the worst for all. 

So many people been mislead, so sad!</utt><utt uid="0">Do you remember that little guy called Franco? I think we had it on Spain a few years and that was a dictatorship state ;)

If i say, we wont go BACK to that dictatorship stat and you dont understand anything, at least, dont put words in my mouth that ive not said.
You know, prensa española, manipuladora and some assholes try to manipulate too. I wonder why we want freedom</utt><utt uid="2">Dont get cocky for a sleep of words, I have read enough of your post and the likes of you, to get a pretty good idea what you think and mean, and that scares the shit out me.

You, and people like you, hide the behind the appealing imagery idea of “oppressors” vs “freedom fighters”, thus legitimizing the actions of your leaders and their agendas, and the rest of the people are left to suffer the consequences. This is not new, it has been seen before, and it is amazing that still in the 21th century there are people who fall for that.

Of course, you will attribute what I said to me been a Spaniard with my own agenda, but believe it or not, I am Expat in Spain and a concern citizen, expecially when people waving with huge flags at my face, screaming and demanding freedom from an non existent oppressive state, I worry

</utt><utt uid="2">Vague statements like yours got us where we are and we are in a bad place. Spain is no dictatorship and you know it.</utt><utt uid="0">Have you seen the news today?</utt><utt uid="2">Indeed. Judicial action being taken against politicians who have been warned on many occasions about not spending taxpayers money on an illegal vote. Money has been spent where it shouldnt. Money earned by struggling families, money taken out of hard work, money taken away from better hospitals and schools is being spent illegally.

There is something to be done about Catalonia. Denying that would be naive. But everybody knows Spain is a democratic country and the actions taken by any other EU state would be similar. I am glad that democratic laws have worked today and will continue to do so until 1-O. Hopefully Catalunya will get something out of this.</utt><utt uid="3">What about forbidding events in favour of the referendum or tearing down posters without a judiciary order? What about entering in printing presses to stop them from being distributed, without an order either? Or raiding the HQs of political parties that arent even in government for the damn posters, no order either? What about closing down web pages that promote it, even when they arent owned by the Catalan government? What happened to freedom of expression and association?</utt><utt uid="2">Freedom of expression ends when taxpayers money is used for an illegal cause. Events, posters or whatever promotes and illegal cause are illegal according to a judge. I am not a judge so I cant comment on that but I can tell you that this is not evil Spain treating you unfaiRLy, its first world, welfare state democratic law. Freedom of expression in Spain is real.</utt><utt uid="3">But none of the things I mentioned were paid for with public money, it was all set up by private entities! If promoting and defending what Spain considers illegal causes is illegal why are separatist parties allowed in the first place? Not to mention that this is the country where the Falange is a legal party that runs for elections! Freedom of speech isnt real in Spain just because Spain itself says it is, thats a tautology. It doesnt matter that you arent a judge, what does your conscience tell you about all of this?</utt><utt uid="1">Perhaps things work differently in Catalonia than they do here in Scotland, but here, we pay taxes, they go to the British government and then they give a portion of it back for our government to spend how they see fit.  Our government is then voted for by the people in elections where they say what theyd like to do if elected, they then put forward a programme for government in parliament and if that is voted for by a majority, then thats how the government will act and how it will spend its money.</utt><utt uid="2">It works the same. Everyone in Spain pays taxes, the Spanish Government collects the money and gives a certain amount of money to every autonomous region. The issue is that Catalunya collects a lot of money and doesnt get  back what many and I consider fair.

Elections. We vote a central government and and regional government. They create a budget and have to say what the money will be spent on. The regional government said they would spend money in a referendum. The Spanish government said no you wont because the law, not any dictator, says you cant. Catalan government spends 15 more million in an illegal referendum (that is 30million € now). Because of wrongdoing, politicians get arrested.
</utt><utt uid="1">Okay.  Now the issue becomes, in any possible situation, would Spain be willing to change the law?  If hundreds of thousands of people (probably millions) stand up together and all say they are going to break the law, at what point do you have to accept that the law is wrong?  And if after all of that, you still cant accept that the law is wrong and continue to refuse to change the law and in fact go as far as to use military force to force people to obey that law, at what point are you in the wrong?  I guess what Im asking is, exactly where is the line Spain needs to cross for you to call them fascist?  Because from an outside observers point of view, the line was smashed through somewhere between tearing down civillian posters and sending forces into government buildings to arrest the elected members of government.</utt><utt uid="2">Spain has mechanisms to change the law. You want to amend the constitution? Theres something about 2/3 in congress and the senate. I dont know how it works. You can check it later. Those are democratic mechanisms.

Figures and percentages are not clear. The issue cannot be ignored. However independence would crush Catalunya and Spain. It doesnt matter that all this people show support to the cause. If they were enough, I am not saying that many, I am saying **enough** they could have had more power in the regional parliament and do more. Oh wait, they did less than ten years ago and in the process destroyed Catalunyas most voted party and lost a ton of deputies.

I guess what Im asking is, exactly where is the line Spain needs to cross for you to call them fascist?

For me to call them fascists Spain should have jailed politicians **before** the first referendum, could have revoked autonomy way earlier, could have flooded Catalunya with Guardias Civiles (Spanish police) much earlier, could have banned Puigdemonts presidency etc. That is fascism and not that is going on in Spain.

Regarding the posters thing, I commented something in this thread. The posters give support to a cause deemed illegal by a democratic judicial system because such cause is funded with taxpayers money.
</utt><utt uid="1">So you’re saying that to change to constitution, Catalonia would require the votes of a majority of Spanish elected officials. That’s just not going to happen, is it? Like if Scotland votes to stay in the EU, it doesn’t really matter as it always comes down to what England votes for. </utt><utt uid="3">The constitution is designed to prevent national minorities from ever realising constitutional changes.</utt><utt uid="3">Catalunna receives more money than it deserves from Spain. You are plain laying. The independence is only a smoke curtain to evade prision, the Catalan governments have been stealing money for more than 30 years (Since Puyol) 

The only way to avoid prision is the independence. Luckily for the criminal, many Catalan are just sheep ( easy to brain wash and use)</utt><utt uid="2">I have been reading your post in the forum, and as expat in Spain it helps me understand a bit more the situation in Catalonia, which frankly it scares me reading a lot of post here, so unbalance and full of rhetoric them against us that so belongs to the 1940s. 


So thank you for posting a more balance viewpoint.</utt><utt uid="3">Right, its just a fascist party ruling it. You know, minor details!</utt><utt uid="3">You are a compulsive liar. Spain has no dictatorship. A dictatorship is exactly what Cataluña would sport if the criminal coup succeeded, which would never happen, a few extremist communist dogs can’t defeat the power of an entire nation with mora than 500 hundred years of history. 

</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Great</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Visca la Senyera!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">I jo he descobert aquest subreddit gracies a veure la imatge a /r/place </utt><utt uid="1">Same here lol</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">[ejeem... per la posteritat](https://www.reddit.com/r/place/comments/63838p/10k_updoots_to_make_rplace_a_permanent_feature_of/)</utt><utt uid="1">Per molt que ho tornin a fer, la primera vegada és única.</utt><utt uid="1">yo get the updoots[^*](https://www.reddit.com/r/tmsbmeta/comments/5xnirl/about_thankmrskeltalbot/)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Qui eren els de factori aquests? Es un sub redit o alguna cosa? Els estava intentant aixafar i no podia =P</utt><utt uid="1">És un subreddit dun videojoc anomenat Factorio, els quals estaven en aquell lloc abans que nosaltres i per tant vam tenir que compartir espai.</utt><utt uid="0">Ara me informat i em fa mal haver-hi fotut la grapa al seu terreny 😫</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Gràcies!

_Ryn ni yma o hyd     
ryn ni yma o hyd     
er gwaetha pawb a phopeth      
er gwaetha pawb a phopeth      
er gwaetha pawb a phopeth      
ryn ni yma o hyd!_</utt><utt uid="1">Dafydd Iwan per sempre! </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Gràcies!
Thank you so much!
Diolch iawn!
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Thank you brothers! Your support is much appreciated!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Now I think, maybe Spanish government wants Catalunya to get independent as well. /s</utt><utt uid="1">Its all a secret plan of theirs! :P</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">My cousin has been arrested. We cant believe it.</utt><utt uid="1">I hope he can be back with your family soon.</utt><utt uid="0">Thanks so much for your compassion.</utt><utt uid="1">I hope the jail is confortable, he will be there at least 15 years. Traitors, criminals and thieves go to prison... is really anyone surprised? </utt><utt uid="2">No one is surprised, Spain is exceeding our expectations on how dumb they are, that is all.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Sou grans!, No defalliu!!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Catalans, lEspagne agonisante crie sa faiblesse.

Espagne, es-tu si repoussante que tu en es réduite à utiliser la force?</utt><utt uid="1">LEspagne a toujours considéré que négocier avec des séparatistes est un signe de faiblesse. Ils ont perdu Cuba de la même façon, en refusant daccepter leurs demandes dune plus grande autonomie et en les réprimant quand les Cubains ont compris que leur seule alternative était lindépendance.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Hola Marrameucastanyes, gràcies per la teva aportació.

Les normes del sub són normes de comportament general, és a dir, són normes sobre com comportar-se en aquest sub i sobre com interactuar, no sobre quin contingut és apropiat i quin no ho és pel sub, que no en tenim.

En el passat he tingut problemes amb usuaris que es dediquen a posar mems en aquest sub. La intenció del sub no és pas la de convertir-se en un echo-chamber de cap ideologia ni de convertir-se en un shithole. Tampoc ho és la de convertir-se en un lloc estricte i de conversació seria.

Aquest missatge va adreçat a tots els usuaris del sub, modereu la quantitat i la qualitat dels mems de totes les ideologies. Això no vol dir que ara hi hagi un problema, que no nhi ha, però escric aquest missatge amb previsió del que pot passar. No voldria haver de prendre més mesures controvertides al respecte.</utt><utt uid="1"> tenir que

No vull ser un perepunyetes però Pompeu Fabra testà maleint des de la tomba. </utt><utt uid="0">Edited, gràcies. Estava acabant de fer el post:

https://www.reddit.com/r/catalunya/comments/70bz1v/soy_alicantino_valenciano_y_espa%C3%B1ol_y_hay_cosas/dn2xf5a/?context=3

Amb castellà i el meu cap encara estava amb dues coses al mateix temps.</utt><utt uid="2">Si podem posar-nos perepunyetes, també se tha colat conversació seria</utt><utt uid="1">Tela quin bloc de text!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Això si!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">LEstatut dAutonomia de Catalunya que és una llei orgànica estipula clarament que la Generalitat té tot el comandament sobre els Mossos dEsquadra, per tant era evident que passaria això.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Al final el que paga manda, quien paga los Mossos ?</utt><utt uid="1">Els Mossos son competència de la Generalitat i molts dells també indepes. No li posarán res fàcil als picoletos. </utt><utt uid="2">A més lestat lo primer que faria seria carregar-sels o diluir-los amb la GC amb la baixada de sou  corresponent. No tenen alternativa, o donen suport als catalans o adeu Mossos.</utt><utt uid="1">No sé por qué te downvotean, es un argumento válido. Juraría que los Mossos dEsquadra cobran directamente del Ministerio del Interior. Si se mantienen al margen tienen una razón justificada para hacerlo no? Los pobres tienen familias que mantener.</utt><utt uid="2">Le downvotean porqué no defiende el independentismo ni este referendum.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Resulta muy curioso como se alega que los Mossos dependen de la Generalitat porqué lo dice la ley. Esa ley sí que parece que debe cumplirse y nombrarse pero no otras.</utt><utt uid="1">Hay mobilizaciones en las calles de 1 milion o mas de personas durante 7 años que pida lo contrario?</utt><utt uid="2">I think youre confusing democracy with some sort of mob rule.</utt><utt uid="3">Silly him thinking democracy is about people ruling themselves.</utt><utt uid="2">Again that is gross oversimplification of democracy that conveniently fits your agenda. </utt><utt uid="3">Right, my agenda being able to exercise my fundamental rights, rights that your constitution prohibits.

You wont win, thats why youre here trolling people, youre just trying to provoke people, but hey, thats okay.

By the way, *votarem*.</utt><utt uid="4">Honestly asking, disregard my username. What is the percentage needed in the referendum to declare independance? 1 million is a lot of people, but against the nearly 7.5 million that Catalunya has in population it doesnt sound as much. I cant seem to find this piece of information. Also, do you think independance will be declared fully for all of Catalunyas provinces or will each province be able to vote to stay? I imagine that not all provinces have a majority in people who want independance. Thanks.</utt><utt uid="3">There is no set minimum requirement, but if its some ridiculously low number (hundreds) it would be taken into consideration, but legally speaking it would be enough to have just 1 person voting, its a whole different matter if it would be given the proper respect.

 1 million is a lot of people, but against the nearly 7.5 million that Catalunya has in population it doesnt sound as much

First of all the number of people who can actually vote is around 5,5 million

1 million people casting their votes far outweigh 4,5 million people (supposedly) forfeiting theirs.

Thats why theres no set minimum, people would just boycott elections if they didnt feel like they could win. And you have to ask yourself why dont they even bother campaigning or voting, they know theyll lose, so they prefer to sabotage the entire thing.

This goes against the laughable idea that the indepes are some very vocal minority that tries to enforce its agenda on everyone. If that were the case, it would be easy to put them in their place by voting NO. But to hell with voting, ESPAÑA NO SE VOTA, as the ultras said a few days ago.

This referendum is for the entire Catalan region, in the future it would be up to the politicians/people of each province to propose its own referendum if they wish to go back to being under Spain.

There has to be some order, you cant insert clauses for every possible change under 1 vote. You do the primary referendum and if youre not satisfied with the result you do one thats important to you, that way the majority in every region can be respected. At least thats my opinion.

You can also consult the results from the latest elections in Catalunya, for the most part the votes correspond to ones stance on independence. The only somewhat possible scenario is that BCN would be able to draw enough NO votes to put some sort of a challenge, the rest are fairly pro-independence through and through.

I think it would be more than 1 million, more than 2 even, but thats only if there wouldnt be any problems with the voting process, like the police physically stopping people from voting, or taking away the urnes etc.

If you let Catalunya vote, youll see that YES would win.</utt><utt uid="4">Thanks for the answer. This was my impression too. I think this time around the Spanish government will have to take this seriously: grant the right for referendum and start campaigning against it as usual in a democratic way, if they ever hope to have a chance to keep the country together. Not saying that they will, but they should at least try to do it the democratic way.
 There has to be some order, you cant insert clauses for every possible change under 1 vote. You do the primary referendum and if youre not satisfied with the result you do one thats important to you, that way the majority in every region can be respected. At least thats my opinion.

Although that makes sense to me, I feel it is awfuly vague for such a process, since not everyone agrees with a the end justifies the means way of doing things. I imagine that based on the execution of this split from Spain there would be people that might change their vote, either in favor or against. Is there a proposal of what the Catalan country would become, as well as details of the steps needed for the autonomy to get there? Like a sort of Plan Ibarretxe of Catalunya, or more information on the split? Im looking for facts more than opinion which I believe exist since there is so much faith in the movement. Thanks.</utt><utt uid="0">This referendum  doesnt accomplish enought guarantees to be trusted. Take a look about how it was redacted. It doesnt accomplish even the Catalonian parlament rules. Last polls says that 61% catalonians doesnt think this referendum is clean enough to take a decision of such relevance as the unilateral independence.

And last elections the independent block got 48% support in votes, but because parlamentary distribution rules they got more than 50% of deputies. To start the referendum and take some crucial decisions the Catalonian paralment has some rules the independent parties violated those. As easy as that. And of course they didnt respect spanish constitution.

And as you said tons of details arent even written, revelated,... people arent well informed about consequences of this. Its like a jump to nowhere.</utt><utt uid="5">I love how people opposed to the referendum are able to pull out all these polls and election results but refuse to let the Catalans actually vote on their political future. In a few years time, I predict that you will all rue this strategy.</utt><utt uid="4">Well they do have the argument that they are going against the law because the law is wrong. So trying to convince the rest of Catalunya that the referendum doesnt actually break the natural law of men because it is democracy by definition makes sense if this is what they are thinking, since they need to give some kind of guarantee to the people that the cause is worth fighting for and as such, worth to risk voting in an illegal referendum for. 

The only sure thing that this will produce is more conflict, scalating the amount of voters to the nationalist party.

The official motives seems to slide on most Catalan people, and the reasons why they are betting heavily on this are very different for different people. 

I can understand a bit the right sided mind, the things are not as good as they were before the crisis, we have money but the Spanish state is taking exagerationall/exageration of the money for themselves!. Overly simplistic way of reducing democracy to themselves, but understandable.

The left side though, I dont quite get it yet. It looks like they use the argument of oppression quite too often, and are left bleak when it comes to actually explaining oppression. Franco comes up a lot, but he didnt do anything for democracy or for Spain, they hate him too. And arresting some people because they were being asses jumping on police cars and breaking street panels / hanging signs in other peoples property is not oppression, thats law enforcement. I dont know how they expect to rule a country where all of these issues arent handled by law.</utt><utt uid="3">The Constitution isnt a law.</utt><utt uid="0">Certainly isnt an ordinary law,  its the main law which has to be respected by all the citizens but mainly designed to be respected by the rest of laws in a country (most civilized countries, if not all have one).</utt><utt uid="3">Its up to you to make the distinction whats to be respected and what not. A constitution in itself means nothing, as I already said before, NK has one, UK doesnt - so how come its such a big deal to have one?

Youre trying to pass it as something so fundamental that a society cant live without, or that its such an ultimate source of all laws that without it there would be anarchy on the streets.

Get over it, constitutions are in direct conflict with human rights, at least when it comes to self-determination, and this *will* be addressed sooner or later.

Of course, with people like you who would rather defend a piece of paper than peoples rights, it would be later than sooner.</utt><utt uid="0">I dont want to live in a country in which each one could freely choose which laws should be respected. If thats your plan for Catalonia, better inform people before.

And no matter how many times you repeat that boring, but ultra dangerous lies about civil rights or human rights in Catalonia. They always will be lies.

</utt><utt uid="3"> which laws should be respected

Except that its not a law.

 They always will be lies.

I guess the only truth for you is VIVA FRANCO then</utt><utt uid="0">Oh man, another time. If a spaniard defends law, constitution or the rules of democracy he must be a falangist. You really need to read more. 

By example, Why dont you look for Joan Coscubiela speech the day Catalonian parlament aproved the illegal referendum ? And look about his personal life. youll learn a lot.

The link:

https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=efv9gWVsB0o</utt><utt uid="1">Having BLACK SLAVES was legal in your beloved country not so many years ago, and to be more precise, Spain was the last country to abolish slavery.

40 years ago, if you were a woman and commited adultery, there was a LAW, that sentenced you at least, with 4 years at jail. But hey! if you were a man...NO PROBLEM!

You are a freak, in not so many years your ideas will be sand in the wind, since they are more suitable for the last century rather for the current one.

Or you can move to Turkey or Saudi Arabia, those countries share your point of view regarding a lot of issues.

Europe or Western countries are not your place, downvote and move on.

</utt><utt uid="0">Not a single Western or European country laws admits a separatist referendum right now. Not even EU and Catalonia situation doesnt fit the UN cases to allow this kind of referendum. Obviously Im talking about your unilateral position.

And I dont downvote, its a kids game.

And, as usual, when you dont agree, you assign me the worst you can find only to disqualify me. But reasons ? Not a single one.</utt><utt uid="1">Of course they dont, there is no need to have it in their own constitutions, its on the World Declaration of Human Rights, that rule is above any constitution, so all the constitutions obey the rule.

I am not charging against you, I am charging against your ideas, those ideas include to silence me and my people.

You wont achieve it, no matter how hard you, and your goverment try.</utt><utt uid="2"> Not a single Western or European country laws admits a separatist referendum right now. 

Not true at all. In Canada, we had 2 referendums in the recent years (1980 and 1995) for the independence of Québec. Sure, Canada did not respect laws around the referendums, but, at the very least, they accepted the referendum game because its the only good way to solve those issues. They didnt try to block democracy, only circumvent it.
</utt><utt uid="0">I sincerely apologize if Im wrong and, to be honest, If you were so kind to link Canada laws about the independence referendum Ill take a look to them.

Thanks in advance!!</utt><utt uid="3">Thats all fine and dandy, except that I dont care. Im just here to inform you trolls that they *will* vote, and nothing you say here will make a difference - youre wasting your time.</utt><utt uid="0">You love to insult. You need to relax.</utt><utt uid="3">Thats rich, playing the victim.

Go burn some flags.</utt><utt uid="1">You cant be more wrong, and please, learn a lil more english dude, its pretty crappy.

But maybe you are uncapable of more.</utt><utt uid="0">Maybe Im uncapable of a better English, I admit it. But Im sure you could express your positions without insulting other ones. It could be refreshing for your soul. Try it!!</utt><utt uid="1">Since you are defending violence against freedom of speech and ideas, yes, I will insult you, and consider yourself lucky that we, the catalans are truly a peacful nation, because if we were like you, or your masters ( you are only a hound ) we would be doing what you did to our people not so many years ago.

Beware.</utt><utt uid="0">So you say Im defending violence against ideas or freedom of speech ?

Oh man, another example of your tactics. You cant qoute I defend that positio . Those Catalonians were arrested because they didnt accomplish a law. Not because their ideas or their declarations.

And you finish menacing me ?</utt><utt uid="1">Demaqué? Ah... Demagogia... Si quieres entender lee un poco, aprende de tus errores y entenderás.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Está vez han reculado.

http://amp.lasexta.com/noticias/nacional/mossos-desquadra-aceptaran-ordenes-fiscalia-pese-compartir-decision-interior_2017092359c69f080cf27caff63cd3b6.html</utt><utt uid="1">Els hi donen llargues un altre cop per a evitar l enfrontament directe.</utt><utt uid="0">Y si finalmente los Mossos traicionan la confianza que puedan depositar en ellos el resto de cuerpos de seguridad, ya nadie podrá confiar en ellos. Nunca.

Desgraciadamente seguro que se contempla ese escenario, y otros peores. Policia y GC no tienen razón alguna para fiarse de ellos ciegamente.</utt><utt uid="1">Quieren que en las fotos de 1-O salgan los Mossos robando urnas y deteniendo a Puigdemont, pero no la tendrán. Antes arderá Troya.</utt><utt uid="0">Algunos es eso lo que queréis.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Luego dirán que si se aplica el 155 será un golpe de estado del gobierno español. Y probablemente, tampoco aceptarían esa autoridad. 

Esta es una jugada MUY arriesgada. Ordago a la grande. No es cosa de broma.

Madre mía la que se está gestando. </utt><utt uid="1">No he comprendo tan bien, quien tu piensa que es arriesgando. El gobierno espanyol o los mossos/la generalitat?</utt><utt uid="0">I think that if Mossos disobbey direct orders from Spain Government Security Departments. Central Goverment, officially, cannot trust in them to enforce central laws, orders or judges. Its a police task force of 17.000 who, it seems, doesnt want to accept orders from central authorities, only those from Catalonian secesionist government.

Puts them almost in a pure rebellion status, they arent politicians or citizens, they are armed civil servers.

I see a very serious risk in that decision.</utt><utt uid="2">Who cares right? Theyre gonna vote anyway.</utt><utt uid="2">No, the central government wanted to take control of Mossos illegally and they refused. They don´t have that right.</utt><utt uid="0">Sorry, but the law says that they have that right when specific operations must be attended and coordinated. Wheter you like it or not.</utt><utt uid="0">Sorry, but the law says that they have that right when specific operations must be attended and coordinated. Wheter you like it or not.</utt><utt uid="2">No, we dont have that law. We have a law for taking control of Mossos but they didnt use it. They used false excuses to take that control and Mossos refused the bullshit. If they want control they can aply martial law 155 before the eyes of the whole planet.</utt><utt uid="0">In this thread you can find that law. Ley Orgánica de Fuerzas de Seguridad, art. 46.</utt><utt uid="2">I love how you get downvoted simply for commenting on the legal situation is an objective, honest manner. Really shows the mentality of the pro-independence crowd here: no desire at all for dialogue, certainly no desire for the sobering reality of the situation and the potential consquences of directly disobeying the Constitution.</utt><utt uid="2">I love how its just one week away from the referendum.</utt><utt uid="1">People can die. I m sorry for all the brain washed poor souls. Spain will remain the same, but your physical integrity is in jeopardy. 

Do what the law says or accept the consequences. </utt><utt uid="2">What are exactly those consequences? Maybe you’re the brainwashed poor soul, eaten by the multimillionaire Spanish media, all of them with the same script. What happens if the central government decides to take action and apply article 155 but the EU says it’s way too much and force them to make a legitimate referendum? I would laugh so hard I might pee myself. </utt><utt uid="0">A policial armed force declared in rebellion against central government forces ?

No one with common sense wants that scenary.</utt><utt uid="2">If that happens be prepared for secessionism to spread like fire... think about Euskadi, Paìs Valencià, Galicia, all of them have independence movements on their own and in case of any fire from the Guardia Civil in Catalonia this will just explode, no one will ever support PP again, game over, insert coin. :’) </utt><utt uid="0">I really dont know what are you trying to say. Would you see that scenary as a possitive force ?</utt><utt uid="2">No, it’s the worst case-scenario, but still is the central government to blame on it, they didn’t want to talk, now face the problem. </utt><utt uid="1">That is never going to happen. The EU is with the law and the Spanish constitution. </utt><utt uid="2">Yeah, sure, we all know how fake politics are, in case they feel is better to be on the Catalan side, they will, and the weapon the central government had will turn against them. </utt><utt uid="1">Catalan side is the loser side. A few cannot win over an entire country. You don’t know what you are talking about. </utt><utt uid="2">L’antic régim con sempre... amb la força no fas res, sol•lament crear més independentisme. </utt><utt uid="1">You will be bitter until your very end. When the “independent fiesta” is over you will be the same sad Spanish citizen. </utt><utt uid="2">Saps que será lo millor després del 1-O? La posibilitat d’un referéndum sobre la monarquia. Siiiii per fa per fa...!!! Hi han tantes coses que es prodríen camviar a Espanya que no puc parar de riure. </utt><utt uid="1">There is nothing needing of change right now. Focus in becoming a better individual and stop following your local politics wacky demands. 

If you wandered just a little over the world you would know by now that tor country is a great place to live with ton of privileges. The u depende would change all that, for the worse. 

I don’t want to live worse, I would never compromise my family’s future over some delusional aspiration. </utt><utt uid="2">Violence is Spains democracy!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ley Orgánica de Fuerzos y Cuerpos de Seguridad (de todos, estatales, autonómicos, locales,...) Artículo 46 .. tercer párrafo, En el resto de casos...

Es una ley, digo yo que los Mossos también tendrán que cumplirla ¿ no ? 

https://www.policia.es/cnp/normativa/normativa_lo_1986_02_tit_4_cap_1.html

Artículo 46

Cuando las Comunidades Autónomas que, según su Estatuto, puedan crear Cuerpos de Policía no dispongan de los medios suficientes para el ejercicio de las funciones previstas en el art. 38,1 y 2 c) de la presente ley, podrán recabar, a través de las Autoridades del Estado el auxilio de las Fuerzas y Cuerpos de Seguridad del Estado, correspondiendo en este caso a las Autoridades gubernativas estatales la determinación del modo y forma de prestar el auxilio solicitado. 

En caso de considerarse procedente su intervención, las Fuerzas y Cuerpos de Seguridad del Estado actuarán bajo el mando de sus Jefes naturales.	

En el resto de los casos, cuando en la prestación de un determinado servicio o en la realización de una actuación concreta concurran, simultáneamente, miembros o Unidades de las Fuerzas y Cuerpos de Seguridad del Estado y de la Policía de la Comunidad Autónoma, serán los Mandos de los primeros los que asuman la dirección de la operación.
</utt><utt uid="1">Ei, saps què?
Votarem.</utt><utt uid="0">Tranquilo que de momento los Mossos no tienen interés en impedírtelo.</utt><utt uid="1">Then theres really no point in beating around the bush here, we all have TVs, we saw the farce, now we can go on with our lives and vote on Sunday.</utt><utt uid="1">Diu clarament que els mossos haurien de soŀlicitar auxili abans que hi puguin participar les forces i cossos de seguretat de lestat.</utt><utt uid="0">Lee el tercer párrafo, En el resto...., en operaciones específicas y concretas dirigidas por el estado central, el mando recae en las fuerzas del estado central.</utt><utt uid="1">És que no coincideixen perquè les competencies són dels Mossos.</utt><utt uid="0">Ese párrafo es bastante claro. En operaciones concretas donde participan varias fuerzas de seguridad, las estatales tienen el mando. No es interpretable. Las operaciones para frenar el referendum (como las antiterroristas) entran en ese supuesto.

Ese párrafo no quita a los Mossos sus competencias habituales.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Ja el vam matar a cops al Born!</utt><utt uid="0">Matarem Franco*; en català no interferit pel castellà el complement directe no porta preposició. </utt><utt uid="0">Estic molt relaxat, passa que no vull que el català es converteixi en un dialecte del castellà. Tots ens hem de comprometre amb el català genuí per assegurar-ne la supervivència. Que sàpigues que estic totalment dacord amb el teu comentari i lhe puntuat en positiu. :)</utt><utt uid="0">Això! Això! I quan hi hagin anuncis a la televisió a fer catalanets i catalanetes!</utt><utt uid="1">El català, a diferència daltres llengües, té una autoritat central que cal respectar si esperem presentar-nos com a persones serioses. Òbviament pots escriure com la PAWN GANG si vols.

No és cap problema tenir una errada honesta, tots som influenciats per el castellà, però agafem les correccions dels companys amb bon esperit!</utt><utt uid="1">Aleshores són els dialectes o és que no tagraden les correccions? Aclarat.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">L1 dOctubre teniu tots una cita!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">LAgost del 2014 vaig emigrar per feina als Estats Units i vaig votar SÍ SÍ el 9N. Ara que torno a finals de Juliol arribaré a temps per votar de nou SÍ en el referèndum del 1 doctubre.

Espero que tot això sigui una bonica metàfora de la fi dun cicle i un nou començament.

Encara recordo quan a linstitut la gent em deia la catalufa i William Wallace (aquest, de fet, mola bastant), i reien dient que mai tindríem no ja majoria, sinó nombres suficients per a plantejar res. Quina gràcia. 

Sigui quin sigui el resultat i passi el que passi, la sensació que vaig tenir en aquella manifestació de 2010 no sha esvaït. Alguna cosa sha trencat i ja és irreparable. Costarà més o menys, però amb 34 anys estic segura que no moriré amb un DNI espanyol dins la cartera.

Força i república!

:)</utt><utt uid="1">Ep! Al meu DNI posa que caduca el 2018! No sé jo si això pot ser un senyal...</utt><utt uid="0">El meu, de fet, ja està caducat. Torno el 29 de Juliol i no sé si em val la pena renovar-lo! Puc tirar amb el passaport fins lany que ve.

:D</utt><utt uid="0">Ho sé. Simplement em fa molta mandra fer la cua per renovar-lo. :)

I sí, no crec que renunciï a la nacionalitat espanyola si aconseguim independitzar-nos, de la mateixa manera que a la meva amiga Rebecca no se li passa pel cap renunciar a la doble nacionalitat americana que té a més de la holandesa.

Pragmatisme per damunt de tot.</utt><utt uid="1">Per a tenir Netflix? Si ja tinc filmin ara!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ànims, a veure si tot va bé!.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Som-hi república!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Algú sap si serà possible votar per correu? No estic visquent al país i no crec que pugui ser-hi l1 doctubre. </utt><utt uid="1">Registrat al cens de catalans a lestranger!</utt><utt uid="0">Mestudiaré el tema, la putada és que estic empadronat a un pis de Catalunya on ja no visc i no menteraria si marriba allà la carta del cens. En qualsevol cas, gràcies pel consell!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Mencanta lenunciat de la pregunta.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Endavant les atxes!!!!</utt><utt uid="1">Violent.... 😋</utt><utt uid="0">Nop. http://blogs.sapiens.cat/batecsclassics/2013/03/29/endavant-les-atxes/

Però jo també creia que era un castellanisme de destral.</utt><utt uid="1">Ja sé que és! Era conya per les reaccions que aquesta paraula comporta a Espanya 😋</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Molt bo aquest [meme](https://twitter.com/escudellat/status/873128093803618305) 😁</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Vinga vaaaaaaa repúblicaaaaaa!!!! :)))</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Is this the first time someone takes a stand to respect people from Catalonias rights?</utt><utt uid="1">Nah, EFA has been doing this for a few years actually, but its still meaningfull.</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Thank you for taking the time to write this! ♥️🇵🇹</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Força desde Portugal!

</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Seeing this I really start to wonder where spanish people got their argument about being hated by other countries from. Because so many great people like you have taken the time to show support. Thank you so much!</utt><utt uid="1">Dont get me wrong, i dont hate Spain ! I love Spain and i have so many spanish friends. But actually, the fact that i know so many spanish guys makes me an even bigger supporter of Independence. Most of them simply dont understand whats going on in Catalunya. They think nothing has to change and even show contempt over catalan culture. I always simpathized with catalan pretensions, but i accepted a federal solution, but over the years i talked with so many spanish over this that i actually think you have to be independent.</utt><utt uid="1">Well actually check the [black legend](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Legend).

Spain always had a mean streak about it - colonial times were hard, war in the netherlands was an assholery contest, their civil war in the 20th century was cruel, the repression that followed equally so.

Portuguese have a ton of forts on the border for a reason, and we had to fight them off plenty.

But to paint it as the villain of history is unfair. All other great powers were capable of great cruelty.

In this case, they are being brutish about it and that is amplifying the crispation the catalans feel about the central government. This is getting them riled up.

We dont need trouble in spain now, particularly when the other powers in the EU just love it.

On the other hand, I like catalonia a lot and they deserve respect. In a way, other than the twist of fate, we could be in their place.</utt><utt uid="2">**Black Legend**

The Black Legend (Spanish: La Leyenda Negra) is a style of tendentious, subjective historical writing or propaganda that demonizes Spain, its people and its culture in an intentional attempt to damage its reputation. There is much documented evidence of atrocities by all European nations during the conquest of the Americas, and the Inquisition represented a period of cruel excess; however, the Black Legend lays this legacy on the Spanish without balance and as a somehow intrinsic element of Spanish character. The Black Legend propaganda originated in the 16th century, a time of strong rivalry between European colonial powers. Though the term black legend for describing this anti-Spanish mythology was coined by Emilia Pardo Bazán in a conference, Paris, April 18, 1899, Julián Juderías was among the first to describe and denounce this phenomenon.

***

^[ [^PM](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=kittens_from_space) ^| [^Exclude ^me](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiTextBotmessage=Excludemesubject=Excludeme) ^| [^Exclude ^from ^subreddit](https://np.reddit.com/r/catalunya/about/banned) ^| [^FAQ ^/ ^Information](https://np.reddit.com/r/WikiTextBot/wiki/index) ^| [^Source](https://github.com/kittenswolf/WikiTextBot)   ^]
^Downvote ^to ^remove ^| ^v0.27</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Quick reminder to keep the discussion civil.

If you detect harassment/comments that are not appropriate please use the report feature.</utt><utt uid="1">A bones hores!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">[Piulada original](https://twitter.com/JulianAssange/status/906639579838644224)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">If Assange thinks something like Tiannamen is going to happen in Spain then there are three possible options:

1) He has no clue about how things work in Spain

2) He is going mental after 7 years locked in an embassy.

3) Both are correct.</utt><utt uid="1">Just a reminder that spanish governament has allways mantained the possibility of military and that Catalonia holds a peaceful disovedience movement, so he achieved a **quite good comparision**.</utt><utt uid="2">No harán falta tanques. Con la guardia civil y los mossos bastaría supongo. Además que los peajes son carísimos y llevar los tanques por nacional es complicado XD</utt><utt uid="0">Its simply ridiculous (and obviously a deliberate propagandistic strategy) to compare the spanish goverment with a dictatorship like China.

There wont be tanks in the streets, even if thats what the catalan nationalists wish.

On the other hand, describing whats going on in Catalonia as a peaceful disobedience movement is not quite accurate. 

1) Its not the common citizens revolting against the goverment, but a group of nationalist politicians who are holding an unilateral vote that **has not been approved by the parliament** and is therefore illegal.

2) These politicians only represent **one third of the catalans**.

3) The referendum will be paid with taxpayer money.

4) Catalonia is not any deprived/oppressed territory but surprisingly **one of the wealthiest, most vibrant regions in Spain** 

5) **Catalonia has also the highest number of politicians charged with corruption in Spain**. Nationalistic parties have controlled the local institutions for decades and have developed a complex network with links to corporations where bribes and money laundering is common practice. 

6) Following this, its quite clear why the local political elites are so keen on cutting of with the central goverment. 


So **any comparison with any popular movement like say, the african-american civil rights is simply ridiculous and embarrasing**. 

Edit: not surprised with the downvotes. The catalanist propaganda machinery is going full steam! This thread is a perfect example of the situation in Catalonia; those who dare to share a different view are bullied and silenced by a noisy minority.
</utt><utt uid="2">1) Thats one of the lies from spanish media. The independence movement started on the citizens, then some political parties saw the opportunity and started selling themselves as pro-independence. At 2012 there was a massive demonstration (estimated 1,5 milion people in barcelona) called Catalunya, nou estat dEuropa (Catalonia, a new Europe state) while catalan government wasnt pro-indepence, at most, they were trying to get a pacte fiscal.

2) Another false statement. They have 72 deputies out of 135 (53%), while the anti-independence parties hold 52 deputies (38%). Media tries to play with this number by stating the number of votes, which is 48% pro-independence (which is far from one third), and hide the votes of anti-independence thats 39%.

4) It is one of the wealthiest regions of spain, and while I agree its not getting oppressed, Im sure it could be way richer if money wasnt spent on empty airports in Ciudad Real, Huesca or Castellón, or if the Trans-European rail network went through Tarragona (a highly industrialized region in catalonia) instead of Monegros (a desert)

5) ermm... What? Where did you get this information from?? Inhat country do you live in? Information taken from spanish media: http://www.elmundo.es/grafico/espana/2014/11/06/5458f3c1268e3e962f8b457b.html http://www.eleconomista.es/seleccionMS/noticias/7336771/02/16/El-coste-de-la-corrupcion-en-Espana-mas-de-7500-millones-saqueados.html

I agree though that a comparisson of Catalonia with any dictatorship is planely wrong. Were not there yet and hopefully wont be.</utt><utt uid="2"> Its not the common citizens revolting against the goverment, but a group of nationalist politicians 

This statement ignores everything done before and after 2012 by individuals and groups.

 These politicians only represent one third of the catalans.

Theres an easy way to prove them wrong: celebrate the referendum. Its just papers into boxes, whats scary about that?

 The referendum will be paid with taxpayer money.

Yeah, nothings free. I also happily pay for the roads and dont drive.

 Catalonia is not any deprived/oppressed territory but surprisingly one of the wealthiest, most vibrant regions in Spain.

Neither were the British or the Scottish. Being oppressed is not a condition sine qua non.

 Catalonia has also the highest number of politicians charged with corruption in Spain. 

And hopefully well ditch them. That doesnt invalidate the wish to be independent.

 Following this, its quite clear why the local political elites

No, its not the political elites. Its the people. Since the 70s. But we cannot know what portion of the people wants that because Spain is afraid of asking.

 So any comparison with any popular movement

Repeat it again and maybe itll become true.</utt><utt uid="1">Apparently some people preferd their money going to *Fundación Francisco Franco* rather than a ballot..

Fun fact, a proindependence NGO even presented a campaign for cititzens to pay the ballots and lots of people was into it!</utt><utt uid="0">Mentioning Franco, who died 42 years ago, is always the last resort in any argument with a separatist. I was expecting it sooner or later. Here it is! :-)</utt><utt uid="2">The Fundación is alive and well. And the francoists still wiggle around our countrys politics.</utt><utt uid="1">I didnt mention Franco, I said *Fundación Francisco Franco*, which is more thsn alive, but whatever fits your speech  :)</utt><utt uid="0">1) Again, these groups and individuals account for just one third of the catalan society. They nominate themselves as the only true catalans and behave quite agressively against those who dontvshare their views. Fun fact: they even have a derogative term for the catalans whose parents/grandparents migrated from other parts of Spain, charnego. Xenophobia, classism, jingoism are common traits of the catalan nationalist movement, very close to other xenophobic parties in Europe like Liga Nord in Italy.

2) Again, the referendum has not been approved by the Parliament and theres no guarantee its not will be manipulated. Theres not been a proper campaign for the remain option since the (enormously biassed) catalan regional goverment only backs the pro-independence vote. A vote in this circumstances is not legitimate and resembles very much to those rigged elections held in countries like Venezuela.

3) You pay for the roads because there are laws that make you. Again, this referendum is illegal, and using taxpayer money would constitute misappropiation.

4) Being oppresed is the main reason argued by the catalan nationalistic movement to ask for independence. Obviously, if you are the second wealthiest region in the country its obvious this argument is false.

Scotlands GDP per capita is below that of England and below the british average. 

Catalonias GDP per capita is way higher than the rest of Spain.

5) The push for independence comes primarily from the catalan political elites. These are highly interested on keeping the corruption network created along the past 35 years and not being held account for their actions.

6) The majority of people in Catalonia are either not interested or against independence. The fact that the minority who want it is noisy doesnt mean its a popular movement.</utt><utt uid="2">1) narrow minded people exist everywhere, xarnego is no worse than guiri, I dont know wheres the connection with independentism there, specially when most independentists always supported the right of the nous catalans (newcomers) to speak their mind in this issue too. Also, again, the only way to know for how many people account each group is to vote, so if you are so afraid of something so innofensive as a referendum stop pulling numbers to support your arguments. Saying that they have this term is a blatant lie as it originated in the occitan culture. About the Lega and the the xenophobia, [the only ones extending their right arm are the Spanish nationalists](http://www.publico.es/uploads/2015/11/19/564de4eb58ec3.jpg).

2) cool, do you want a referendum with warranties or do you want to forbid the referendum? Choose only one because it deauthorizes you to claim the other. The Spanish nationalism does not want to let people vote and complains about shitty voting when people vote anyway? lol

3) cool, make it legal. Its not that difficult. Same problem as 2.

4) independence is pursued by a variety of reasons like cultural divide. The most logical one should be because we want. Also, oppression doesnt need to be economical.

5) oh, you actually repeated that, did it become true?

6) if only there was one way to prove you true, like, idk, everybody writes what they are interested in in a paper, then put the papers in a box and count them all.</utt><utt uid="2">One third? And you tell that he has no clue whats going on??? They win in congressmen and would win in votes if you account for the en comú independentists, which are quite a lot...</utt><utt uid="1"> Its simply ridiculous to compare the spanish goverment with a dictatorship like China.

No, its **not** when not only spain has used such tactics in the past but also mantains them on the table nowadays.

1) Learn what civil peaceful desobedience means, you apparently need it

2) According to whom? Catalan parliment recived a majority of votes (on both direct votes and seats) for proreferendum forces.

3) Fundación Francisco Franco is paid with taxpayer money. That doesnt change catalan civil disovedience argument.

And seriously, doesnt even make sense to reply you any more. You are trying to say that a peaceful civil arguments hat have nothing to do with it.

 Ghandi was bad because flamencos are pink</utt><utt uid="1">Assange is far right trash, supporter of Alex Jones, mens right movement, Trump puppet.</utt><utt uid="2">Theres right-wing independentists too (Estat Català for example), independentism is very wide. Theres also right-wing Spanish republicanism. And right-wing workers parties.

Fortunately they are minorities, and that does not invalidate independentism by itself, or Spanish republicanism, or workers struggle.</utt><utt uid="1">he;s just using rhetoric</utt><utt uid="2">He is just being manipulative. 

Most of us catalans are fed up with nationalist propaganda trying to depint Spain as the enemy to justify secesionism. 

There is a silent majority of citizens whose first priority is not making an identity of hating the other. </utt><utt uid="2">Stop being silent. Make your voice heard. The only ones preventing you from speaking up are the ones forbidding the referendum.

NB: nationalist applies to the Spanish nationalism, too.</utt><utt uid="2">Thats not true at all. We are constantly silenced by the nationalist movement, we are not given any voice and deemed as not true catalans by these patriots. 

Living here the only nationalism we feel.is the catalan one, which is constantly around. </utt><utt uid="3">+5 en 10 minuts. A qui voleu enganyar?</utt><utt uid="2">Brigaders gonna brigade.</utt><utt uid="1">Sembla més aviat alt accounts en realitat. Res que un check ràpid dels administradors de reddit a les seves IPs no pugui solucionar :D</utt><utt uid="2">You could vote in a referendum. Its the Spanish nationalism whos silencing you by forbidding it.</utt><utt uid="2">We havent asked for a referendum, we simply are not concerned about our identity like you are. 

Spanish nationalism is not near half as present in our lives as catalan one is. We are literally bombarded with national symbols and rethoric every single day. 

Regional goverment owned media like TV3 are used as a mean of patriotic propaganda, which can be boring when you not less concerned about your national identity than about the unemployement rate or the healthcare system.

Boring and tiring.</utt><utt uid="2">So if you dont care, why cockblock who is concerned?

Also, not being aware of the shit tsunami coming from the Spanish nationalist propaganda machine might be just because of selective perception.</utt><utt uid="2">We are not cockblocking anything, we just dont want to be part of your theatre play and be used by you.

I would say that precisely catalan nationalism is all about a twisted selective perception of reality.

Ive had these arguments about this nationalist people before and they have always ended up insulting me and calling me fascist. The rest of people who Im certain share my views usually remain silent not to be bullied. </utt><utt uid="2">We are the silent majority but we wont allow a vote to prove it. 

Stop playing victim, ffs. Nobody has been killed for opposing the referendum like G. Agulló was for supporting it. I can invent arguments where they end bullying me too.

Thanks for the ultra fast downvote, put it in an urn :v</utt><utt uid="3">Of course youre not as concerned about your identity, because you already live in a state that protects and promotes it. [Were](http://a2012.kiosko.net/04/08/es/abc.750.jpg) [also](http://a2011.kiosko.net/01/12/es/abc.750.jpg) [bombarded](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xGq7-d-NZSI) [with](http://fundipau.org/lexercit-al-salo-de-lensenyament/) [Spanish](http://www.abc.es/espana/catalunya/barcelona/abci-seleccion-espanola-barcelona-partido-maldito-201701261401_noticia.html) [national](http://www.lavanguardia.com/politica/20161208/412484234393/parada-militar-desfile-infanteria.html) [symbols](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aTC4MPAw4UA) [and](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z7gPL5Wedw0) [rhetoric](http://www.europapress.es/economia/laboral-00346/noticia-rajoy-entrega-medalla-oro-merito-trabajo-gasol-maria-teresa-campos-otros-20170727143509.html), [you just dont pay attention to them because you perceive them as normal.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banal_nationalism)</utt><utt uid="3">**Banal nationalism**

Banal nationalism refers to the everyday representations of the nation which build a shared sense of national belonging amongst humans. The term is derived from Michael Billigs 1995 book of the same name and is intended to be understood critically. Today the term is used primarily in academic discussion of identity formation and geopolitics.

Examples of banal nationalism include the use of flags in everyday contexts, sporting events, national songs, symbols on money, popular expressions and turns of phrase, patriotic clubs, the use of implied togetherness in the national press, for example, the use of terms such as the prime minister, the weather, our team, and divisions into domestic and international news.

***

^[ [^PM](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=kittens_from_space) ^| [^Exclude ^me](https://reddit.com/message/compose?to=WikiTextBotmessage=Excludemesubject=Excludeme) ^| [^Exclude ^from ^subreddit](https://np.reddit.com/r/catalunya/about/banned) ^| [^FAQ ^/ ^Information](https://np.reddit.com/r/WikiTextBot/wiki/index) ^| [^Source](https://github.com/kittenswolf/WikiTextBot)   ^]
^Downvote ^to ^remove ^| ^v0.27</utt><utt uid="3">good bot</utt><utt uid="4">Thank you Esbarzer for voting on WikiTextBot.  

This bot wants to find the best and worst bots on Reddit. [You can view results here](https://goodbot-badbot.herokuapp.com/).  

 ***  

^^Even ^^if ^^I ^^dont ^^reply ^^to ^^your ^^comment, ^^Im ^^still ^^listening ^^for ^^votes. ^^Check ^^the ^^webpage ^^to ^^see ^^if ^^your ^^vote ^^registered!</utt><utt uid="3"> Regional goverment owned media like TV3 are used as a mean of patriotic propaganda, which can be boring when you not less concerned about your national identity than about the unemployement rate or the healthcare system.

One of the things the independence movement has put a lot of emphasis on is using the tools of an independent state to improve the economy, for example by building infrastructure to increase our exports. Theres also the fact that the structures necessary to run the state would create employment by themselves. Meanwhile, the Spanish government sits on its ass waiting for the economic situation to improve on its own.

Also, this years budget has the highest percentage of spending in healthcare and social services. Its not an either/or situation, were separatists *because* we care about those things, not just for reasons of identity.

Edit: By the way, if you dont like what the Catalan press says you can watch or read Spanish media to get the opposite viewpoint, when in the rest of Spain they only get the latter. Thats a testament to the plurality of our society, not of a monolithic Catalan nationalism.</utt><utt uid="1"> we are not given any voice

How so?</utt><utt uid="3">No such thing as silent majority:

48% of voters were 100% for independence. 39% against it. If this silent majority is so silent that they refuse to vote in the elections (not a referendum mind you) then there would be more votes that are 100% for independence. And before you use the argument about CSQeP - remember a census a year ago determined most of their voters were in favor of the referendum, with a considerable amount (60%) also in favor of independence. So no, this silent majority thing is bullshit, everything you say is anecdotal and has 0 backing by fact or statistics.</utt><utt uid="0">Look at my latest post. Please stop twisting figures.

63% of people in Catalonia:

1) Dont want independence

2) Dont care enough to ask for independence

Still, pro-independence option **had literally less votes** than the rest of parties against it.

I dont see why a minority can claim the right to impose their views in such a key issue like creating a new country.</utt><utt uid="3">None of these things are true.

Latest census stated that 80% of people in Catalonia wanted to vote. 40% were in favour of independence. I dont believe in census though as it takes into account tons of people that dont vote. I really dont know where these figures come from though.

In the latest election the parties for independence were JxSi and CUP. PSC, Ciutadans and PP were against it. CSQeP did not position themselves either way but did say they supported the referendum. So no, the independence parties did not have less votes.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">So no debate then? 

At least I keep getting emojis. That must account for something.</utt><utt uid="1">u/raicopk already debated with you. There are more people interested in this independence process around the world than you think, without any need of lobbying by the Catalan government. Not to mention that lobbying is a charged word: Its true that the Generalitat has been pursuing diplomatic contacts with foreign countries, mostly at the parliamentary level, but by using that word youre making it sound like theyve been greasing palms. 

And all the debating youve done is insisting that of course they have without giving any proof, while trying to put the burden to prove a negative (that they havent) on us, when the onus to demonstrate those assertions is on you. So whats the point of debating with someone that argues in such bad faith, again, other than for your own amusement and to let you keep making fallacies?

By the way, I know its only circumstantial evidence and I cant definitely prove it without the IP records, plus the fact that this account is a few months older than the more active one, but [heres a post from a month ago](https://www.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/6szbsb/percentage_of_persons_aged_2024_neither_in/dlil1lo/) of you, an account with very few posts and general activity, butting in a conversation of u/Provenzal, whos also in this thread. And its almost the only thing youve posted in all that time before coming here. I mean, its a huge coincidence, isnt it? Like, we all like a good puppet show every once in a while, but try being more subtle next time, ok?</utt><utt uid="0">Already debated me? Not at all. At least you try a bit harder.

I do suspect some lobbying is going on. Its not an impossible thought outside your bubble. This discrepancy between us cannot be resolved unless one of us hacks into his computer... so lets agree to disagree here. 

My main point is this one: The tweet is very inaccurate and out of context in 21st century Spain. Implying that Spain will send tanks (those black and white one have such a WW2 Nazi-vibe!) is just misleading. Its ridiculous.  I dont buy the we are the poor oppressed underdog narrative and many people think like me in Europe.

Its funny how you are allowed to refer to the other user and yourself as us but you seem so outraged that I have friends in reddit. I must be someones puppet, of course. How can a real individual contradict you on its own accord, right?</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Well, now we know how Putin would like to see things go. Trump in America, Brexit in the EU, Ukraine and Syria in flames, Turkey under a dictatorship, North Korea getting crazier, and now Catalonia. Some people just want to see the whole world burn. Just remember, Spain is the biggest EU nation that doesnt buy any Russia gas so one of the only ones that can tell Russia to fuck off. I liked Julian Ass-angel back when he was apolitical.   </utt><utt uid="1">Congrats, you just compared Catalonia to a fascist, a xenophobic movement, a civil war, a genocide, and two dictatorships. Here you have a cookie 🍪</utt><utt uid="0">In the eyes of Putin, anything that destabilizes his rivals is to his benefit. I was just pointing out that Spain is the only major EU nation not beholden to Russia for natural gas. The enemy of my enemy is my friend and theres no way Putin isnt enjoying watching Spain suffer and the EU the cohesion of the EU being put to further test. This is big league geopolitics, not some sort of snide attempt to put put Puigdemont in the same bed as Erdoğen. Far from it. Just a remark on a macro view of world politics. And do you honestly think Assange would have Tweeted that if he was taking refuge in Beijing instead of Moscow?</utt><utt uid="1">So? Doesnt make anything of what he said untrue. Hes not prorussian either, hes in Ecuadors embassy in London recognized as a political refugee. **You are speaking abour Edward Snowden**.

By your logic yes. Just a reminder that China has been with EUiA in the symposiums.</utt><utt uid="0">My mistake about him being in Russia not London. But the allegations of Assange being in Putins pocket are widespread.</utt><utt uid="1">You simply thought he was snowden lol. If you knew anything about his work you would know hes anything but proPutin, but of course... If he makes people discover what the US goverment has done hes cathegorized as proPutin. Surprise? Idts</utt><utt uid="0">Yes, Snowden is in Russia, but more of a liability than an asset for Putin, who has even floated the idea of sending him back to the USA to be tried for treason. Putin isnt controlling Snowden and Snowden isnt releasing additional information. Assange, however, has come under criticism from both the left and the right for the increasing politicization of Wikileaks and how his releases are seemingly designed not to conflict with Russian interests. </utt><utt uid="1">If he was truly against oppression he would be complaining about how Putin treats his political rivals. Not some Spanish internal dispute where there are no murders by poisoning (or by any other means) and certainly no tanks involved.
This dispute means nothing to him, its just a publicity stunt that his Russian benefactors have encouraged him to be part of.</utt><utt uid="0">This is the unfortunate state of affairs with Assange. And equally unfortunate that people will put this up trying to paint Catalonia in a heroic, with the full support of the international community, rather than seeing through the propaganda and agendas.</utt><utt uid="1">The international community is not paying close attention to any of it... And the EU is not aligning with Assange either. Nationalists would like that full support to be true but thats just not reality.</utt><utt uid="0">Oh I totally agree. I was referencing the original posting of the tweet, not your critique.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Julian Assange suddenly interested in Spanish internal conflicts and speaking in perfect Catalan??? 
Catalan Nationalists are truly desperate. What have they paid him/promised him to get him to copy-paste this text in his twitter feed?

They have chosen the wrong guy though... his credibility in the Trump Era is at an all time low.</utt><utt uid="1">Its called Google translator lol. But yes, he has been bribed as well as Harvard University, Lativian PM, Swiss governament, Carter foundation... Those catalans! With all what they spend in briberies they could erradicate world famine!</utt><utt uid="0">And please note that I am referring to Nationalists and not Catalans as you would have me say in your previous attempt at sarcasm.
I have nothing against Catalans but I find Nationalists very tiring.</utt><utt uid="1">As I said, if you dont like it here you can allways leave (and your other alts too ☺️). Really simple.</utt><utt uid="0">I only have one reddit account and I have not been disrespectful. Maybe you cannot believe than an actual human being disagrees with your world vision.  Sad.</utt><utt uid="0">Jesus. You keep a track of every single person and organisation that has said something remotely favourable to Nationalism! Your attitude proves the point that there is an obsession here.
I would expect Nationalist organisations to do some lobbying -its not a crime- I just think that they need to keep their standards. Assange has been behaving like a Russian puppet lately and the reference to tanks is just ridiculous. </utt><utt uid="1">No dear brigading troll, there are plenty of other examples, but those were just four examples that spaniard media accused of being brided which was **extremelly hilarious** and well... Gotta remember the good laughs!

Btw, if theres an obsession here feel free to leave :D</utt><utt uid="0">I am no brigading troll. I am only a person giving their honest opinion which happens to be different from yours. If you cant hold a debate with someone that disagrees with you then I guess that is part of the problem.

I am glad you find a source of happiness in Spanish media newspapers -I tend to not take news so personally but I guess this isnt such an emotional issue for me.

I dont think it is far fetched to suggest that some lobbying is being carried out by a Regional Government seeking independence. Please look up the term lobbying -I am not suggesting it is bribing. 

Its sad that a rational conversation cant be had and that there is such a level of hysteria around this issue. </utt><utt uid="1"> I am no brigading troll.

And thats why your posts had 10 upvotes (Reverted within time, what a surprise) in just 5 mins on a superchill sub as this one, aha.

 If you cant hold a debate with someone that disagrees with you

Hold a debate? Im allways up for it! Argue with a brick wall that just shouts stereotypes and lies? Watching paint dry out is more interesting

 I tend to not take news so personally but I guess

And do I? Lol. Just said it was hillarious 😉</utt><utt uid="0">This post has been on Popular so you can guess there are other people here other than us. I repeat I only upvote or downvote with this account. I wont stay forever, dont worry. 

Ok, so you are up for a debate. Thats a good start. You have to listen to the other part and not discard their arguments as stereotypes and lies and build up your points. If any of  my points is similar to something you read on Spanish Media that cant be used as a source of discredit per se -you have to argue why it is wrong.

I suspect you are not really looking for a debate but just an echo-chamber where your opinions are echoed over and over again by other users. </utt><utt uid="1">A 20 karma post, of course 😂</utt><utt uid="0">So no debate then?</utt><utt uid="2">Its funny you acuse everyone here of being brigading trolls when my comments got tons of downvotes from your army of patriots. 

Just out of curiosity, how many friends did you call in? Must be a busy day working for the glory of the country. :-)</utt><utt uid="1">I have been arround here for a looong time, you peep(s) are really obvious with it. Come on, not even using elaborated accounts/covered brigading!

 Just out of curiosity, how many friends did you call in?

None, was busy trying to figure a css thing on my sub 😉</utt><utt uid="2">And magically all my comments have -10 downvotes.

Whos the troll here? </utt><utt uid="1">[He used Google Translate](https://twitter.com/HiginiaRoig/status/906790014666907650)</utt><utt uid="1">Speaking perfect Catalan? Cmon man, the last part of his sentence doesnt even make sense. 
And, as it has already been pointed out, his tweet in Catalan is what you get after using Google Translate on the original English tweet....</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Results in the last regional elections held in 2015

http://resultados.elpais.com/elecciones/2015/autonomicas/09/index.html

Very roughly:

-Pro-independence 1.957.348 votes, that is 36% of the total population with the right to vote.

-No-independence 2.074.927 votes. 39% 

-Abstention 1.199.106 votes. 22.5%

So approx. only 1/3 of the population wants independence. 

The rest of it dont. Its simple.

Edit: as expected, a few minor details like not having the majority surely wont stop the glorious new republic of Catalonia to be born. Hilarious :-)</utt><utt uid="1">ProIndependence parties: **1.966.508 votes, 47,80%**

- JxSí: **1.628.714 votes**, a 39,59% of the turn out

- CUP CC: **337.794 votes**, a 8,21% of the turn out

Leaving aside small parties like *Pirates de Catalunya*.

ProReferendum groups with both unionist and independentist parties:

- Catalunya Sí Que Es Pot: **367.613 votes, a 8.94%** of the turn out.

AntiIndependence parties: **1.608.840 votes, a 39,11%**

- Ciutadans: **736.364 votes**, a 17.90% of the turn out.

- PSC: **523.283 votes**, a 12,72% of the turn out.

- PP: **349.193 votes**, a 8.49% of the turn out

48%39% FYI

Tip: if you are gonna manipulate data next time dont include the source.

---------------------

Fun fact: second spanish republic was declared with a plebiscitary (municipal) election which was won by republicans with a 48% of turn out

-----------------------

The point of a referendum is to find out which option is the majority.</utt><utt uid="0">Unio.cat and CatSíqueesPot are not pro-independece.

So again, pro-independence vote is less than no-independence vote, and roughly 1/3 of the adult population with the right to vote.

Great things about numbers is that its something measurable beyond patriotic feelings.</utt><utt uid="1">Unió.cat has no single seat and therefore isnt counted as Pirate Party, an independentist party, isnt either.

And Catalunya Sí Que Es Pot is proreferendum but without an stance on independence due to being built by **both unionist and independentists**, so counting them as unionist or independentist side is complete bullshit.

So again, parties against independence are a minority ;)</utt><utt uid="0">Unio.cat got 109.000 votes even if they didnt gain a seat. These people dont count?

Is this how votes would be counted in a referendum?

The resemblance with Venezuela is scarily accurate...</utt><utt uid="2">Even if you were to add Unió (who by the way positioned themselves in favour of a referendum but against independence) you would still get a minority of Non-independence voters vs Independence voters. Seriously, stop cooking these figures.</utt><utt uid="1">The rest of it dont. Its simple.

Thats REALLY a manipulative interpretation of statistics. If I said that I ask 1000 people on the street to answer my question and only 100 did so and 60 told me they want independence it would be absurd to assume only 60 people of the 1000 want independence.

Abstention numbers cant be count in No-Independece and neither in Pro-Independence. Thats why youve got to stick to the %. Any other interpretation is manipulative.

Only 1/3 of Catalonia has expressed his will pro-Independence. That doesnt mean only 1/3 is pro-Independence. The same way i cant say only 1/3 are unionists. Only 1/3 have expressed they are unionists.

Btw statistics tell us that CSQeP has more independents than unionists, so % turn the other way around.  But Im not going to enter this ideological debate, I just want people to stop taking statistics and getting the numbers they want when they look at them.

Edit: As pointed out by [raicopk](https://www.reddit.com/r/catalunya/comments/6z4ysp/julian_assange_a_twitter/dmtlfmx/?utm_content=permalinkutm_medium=frontutm_source=redditutm_name=catalunya) your analysis takes into account that CSQeP is not unionist. That is even more manipulative than I thought.</utt><utt uid="1">Since when do abstentionists count when making political changes? By that token, no government in the world except those of countries where voting is compulsory is legitimate, since they dont have the support of more than half of the total voting population. And how dishonest of you to include CSQEPs voters in the NO camp, when they explicitly said that they shouldnt be included in either one, [their voters are split on the issue](http://s2.eestatic.com/2017/09/02/actualidad/Actualidad_243738623_45158788_1706x960.jpg) and their leaders are encouraging people to vote in the referendum, legitimating its result.</utt><utt uid="1">Lmao, it doesnt stop here! He even manipulated the sums to fit his agenda! 😂 He didnt even stop on abstentionists and on counting EUiA (way more independentist than most of independentist parties) as unionist haha.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Catalan here. 

This thing about the tanks is simply nonsense. 

</utt><utt uid="1">Nice alt account lol</utt><utt uid="2">A month old account going off about how hes a Catalan and that hes against nationalists.

I dont want to say shill but hes trying way too hard to look like one.</utt><utt uid="0">So just because I disagree with your vision I cant be a true catalan? Lol, this is exactly what I mean!</utt><utt uid="2">I know exactly who those people are who start off by saying Im Catalan and proceed to go on about nationalism and all that crap.

Its the equivalent of Im not racist, but...</utt><utt uid="0">So, your view is that if some other catalan fellow diagree with you then he cant be a true catalan.

This thread is confirming all the stereotypes with you guys, thank you. Intolerant bigots unable to understand that there might exist other people out there with different opinions.

</utt><utt uid="1">Si no saps ni català nano, set nota el fum de pollastre cremat des de la Xina. **Comença el mambo!**</utt><utt uid="2">Being an asshole isnt having a different opinion.</utt><utt uid="3">Looking at the way you and the rest of nationalists over here are adressing the debate makes me realise having a referendum and letting Cataluña go might not be a bad idea after all. We will at last focus on our real challenges instead of worrying about your identity crisis and historical complex.

Honestly, Im deeply ashamed of sharing a passport with people like you. Enjoy your future fascist paradise outside the EU, Im sure countries like Venezuela will be delighted to trade with you.

My only concern is what you will do with the disidents. Hopefully they will be welcomed in the rest of Spain.</utt><utt uid="2">Good, let Catalans vote and there wont be a need to debate if youre a Catalan or not.</utt><utt uid="3">I mean, calling me a shill, typical nationalistic manipulation!</utt><utt uid="4">Are you arguing with your own sockpuppet?</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Jo hi he estat! Increïble!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ha set genial!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Jo sent de Piera (Anoia) he acabat anant a Amposta, pel tema de la via catalana. La primera vegada que ficava els peus en les terres de lEbre i he marxat molt content.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona Diada! Només unes poques hores més fins que pugui prendre una cervesa, és una pena que estic encallat al Regne Unit en el futur previsible. Que ha estat un temps des de la darrera visita.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona Diada catalans!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona Diada des de Holanda!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Em pregunto xq no han fet una versió en anglès daquest 30minuts</utt><utt uid="1">Poseu el link a /rbarcelona i /rspain a veure com reaccionen</utt><utt uid="2">i a /r/europe, que també deixals anar.</utt><utt uid="0">No fa falta, que a Espanya no tenen ambulàncies pediàtriques i encara produïrem un ensurt</utt><utt uid="2">Vaig mirar de fer-ho, però /rbarcelona és només per temes de la pròpia ciutat, no crec que sigui el lloc per un documental de crim i política.

Respecte /rspain, vaig pensar que compartir-ho allà seria potser més buscar problemes que cap altre cosa, encara que potser mequivoco. Convido a qui vulgui a penjar-ho allí si així ho desitja.</utt><utt uid="0">També ha afectat a la ciutat. Trias va ser-ne una víctima per exemple</utt><utt uid="1">I una versió in spanish? A veure quants minuts duraria una emissió pirata a TVE abans que la tallessin</utt><utt uid="2">Bé, la narració és en catala pero moltes entrevistes son en castella. Un espanyol ho pot entendre perfectement 😁.</utt><utt uid="1">EN CRISTIANO POR FAVOR, AQUI TODOS SOMOS GENTE DE BIEN</utt><utt uid="3">de rancio abolengo</utt><utt uid="0">Si sha fet en un dialectes del castellà! 😉</utt><utt uid="1">Oh cert, we are all spaniards on this blessed day</utt><utt uid="2">Està subtitulada en castellà, tens una icona a la part inferior dreta del vídeo!</utt><utt uid="1">Pero eso en Valladolid ni se lo miran, cal difusió</utt><utt uid="2">Visc a Madrid i tens raó, ho he enviat a dues persones i mhan tractat de boig. Que hi farem...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Sembla evident que lEstat Espanyol té tota una sèrie de línies obertes a on lestratègia és treballar en contra del pensament català i el catalanisme polític. Per a això tant els hi val informació veraç com no. Aquesta Operació Catalunya però, hem de tenir molt clar que segueix existint i seguirà fent-se servir dels mitjans espanyols de masses com a altaveu per a la seva estratègia. Tots hem de ser crítics amb els nostres polítics i les nostres institucions, però hem de ser igual o més crítics amb la informació que es faci publica a mitjans espanyols que shan demostrat clarament alineats amb els objectius de lEstat Espanyol. Vivim dins un món a on ens arriba informació en massa de per tots els costats i hem de fer un esforç gros per mantenir-nos crítics.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Quin cinisme el PSC i el PP que han tingut el poder de fer-ho de debó fa anys i panys. Falsos i absurds </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">[Un shekel pel bon goy.](http://prntscr.com/fq09ka)

^cels ^^ennuvolats ^^^amb ^^^^possibilitat ^^^^^de ^^^^^^downvotes</utt><utt uid="1">Upvote per antisemita</utt><utt uid="0">Bon goy.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">O que no ho faci... A mi mentres Dinamarca ho faci, el que la Polònia sexista faci més ven indiferent.</utt><utt uid="1">Com a català visquent a Polònia, no pensis que tot el país és retrògrada i sexista. Aquí hi ha molta gent molt vàlida i com més units estiguem amb tota Europa, millor.</utt><utt uid="0">Tot el país? No ho penso pas, però part de la seva política si, i aquí està el problema, aquests obetenten el poder. I era només el primer exemple que sem va passar. També podia haver-hi canviat per leurodiputat hongarès que volia posar caps de porc a les tanques perquè els refugiats tornessin al seu país.

Què vols que thi digui... jo, units, a qualsevol preu no ho vull estar</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Thats sad. I wish these people could speak Catalan, Sardinian and Italian.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">En aquest llibre es veu que diuen «volta» i no «vegada».  Una mica italianitzat.</utt><utt uid="1">Volta és perfectament correcte. Tot i que ho he sentit més en valencià.</utt><utt uid="2">Can confirm, jo normalment dic volta, encara que a vegades (:P) dic vegà.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Uf! Catalan flags? I diu que la senyera estàndard és un símbol independentista? 

Que ells no en tinguin ni idea de què parlen, mira... però a /r/catalunya ????</utt><utt uid="1">Ha copiat el títol de larticle el qual també és horrible.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">At the end of the day, those flags were ALLOWED.

You can see the final and check it. Bad title.</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">I així es va confirmar el que els científics de tot el món sesperaven: Els catalans tenen un efecte quàntic perceptible a escales humanes. La causa daixò encara és desconeguda, però investigadors de totes les parts del planeta ja estan intentant estudiar diferents fenòmens per descobrir nova física.

Per exemple:

-Els efectes de la gravetat en la superposició quàntica

-Com afecta a la longitut dona de de broglie

-Què és un observador?

-Com col·lapsa la funció dona dun català?

El govern espanyol ja soposa a aquests experiments. Assegura que si la funció dona de molts catalans col·lapsa a lhora es pot arribar a produir un forat negre. Això és realment preocupant perquè incomunicaria Catalunya de la resta del món, cosa que causaria una declaració dindependència immediata i unilateral. Altres consideren que la comunicació encara seria possible si sentrellacen quànticament catalans amb espanyols. El comitè general dètica bioquàntica està estudiant la ètica darrere daquests experiments racials i antinaturals. Ara bé, aquest comitè ha aprovat recentment la creació del LCC (Large Catalan Colider), que disparà catalans a la (quasi) velocitat de la llum per estudiar-ne els efectes relativistes i la composició de la matèria dels catalans. Els primers experiments ja realitzats suggereixen uns avenços impressionants, aquests catalans semblen tenir algun tipus dentrellaçament amb partícules a través de la dimensió temporal, aproximadament per allà el 1714. Algunes teories molt modernes relacionen que lenergia fosca prové dels mal de caps que es provoquen als catalans amb les autopistes i així es justifica la inaturable expansió de lunivers.</utt><utt uid="1">Mare meva</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Hehe, els anglesos diuen la mateixa cosa dels gal·lesos. </utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">HAHAHA Pobre tió</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Recordo que vaig veure al Tió en un top anglès de Tradicions nadalenques més estranyes.
Bàsicament els catalans alimentem a un tronc durant un mes sencer per a després apallissar-lo per a que defequí llaminadures...
Ehem, tot normal...</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">En la meva opinió no hem de fer una estelada a sobre la senyera, la que tenim es queda com està. Tot i així no crec que la diveritat dopinions impedeixi que aquells que ho vulguin la facin... (en un altre lloc dic)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Podria ser una bona idea, però hem de vigilar que no passi com amb els intents de bandera dEspanya, que uns volien fer lactual i els altres la republicana i shan tirat els trastos pel cap. XD

Jo de moment faria la Senyera més gran, i si la cosa avança fem el que dius, ens comptem un dia daquests al vespre (que és el moment que som més usuaris) i canviem la Senyera per lEstelada! :D</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Per fer lestelada proposo utilitzar [el cor vertical que acabem de completar](https://www.reddit.com/r/place#x=547y=768), que serà més fàcil de mantenir, i deixar la senyera tal i com està ara.</utt><utt uid="1">Quedaria bé afegir una mica més de blau.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Podriem posar-li barretina a un dels smileys si tornen a empipar :D</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Otra opcion es seguir avanzando por encima del logo de Dreamcast que seguramente es mas sencillo. </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">https://snag.gy/SksAl4.jpg Jo no se si això és un intent destelada o un intent de desfer el dibuix del cor....</utt><utt uid="1">En teoria intent destelada pel que diuen alguns.</utt><utt uid="2">pregunteu-ho a u/ccs777 no?</utt><utt uid="3">Idees per a que quedi millor? 
https://www.reddit.com/r/place#x=551y=771</utt><utt uid="2">Hi afegim un pixel blanc al mig?? (així:  https://snag.gy/CJfo03.jpg)</utt><utt uid="3">I ho envoltem de blau?</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Quin és lobjectiu ara?</utt><utt uid="1">Mantenir la Senyera i avançar demà.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo també estic posant pixels aixi com puc xD. No sé si serem capaços de fer una estelada xD.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo també estic fent un cop de ma. La idea es menjarnos el cartell aquest que posa Factoria o algo aixi?
</utt><utt uid="1">Sí, però abans hem de col·laborar a mourel cap a la dreta per evitar que durant la nit els americans ens ho petin tot.</utt><utt uid="1">No crec que puguem contra els de /r/factorio com a molt parlant-ho amb ells treurels la primera fila negra de píxels i fer-la groga.</utt><utt uid="2">**Heres a sneak peek of [/r/factorio](https://np.reddit.com/r/factorio) using the [top posts](https://np.reddit.com/r/factorio/top/?sort=topt=year) of the year!**

\#1: [Upbelts to the left! Upvotes are now animated, along with other features.](https://np.reddit.com/r/factorio/comments/4yomv4/upbelts_to_the_left_upvotes_are_now_animated/)  
\#2: [Roses are Red, Violets are Blue.](http://i.imgur.com/d7I9J4M.png) | [60 comments](https://np.reddit.com/r/factorio/comments/58rxz0/roses_are_red_violets_are_blue/)  
\#3: [When you gotta know, at a glance.](http://i.imgur.com/x0A3X5w.gifv) | [104 comments](https://np.reddit.com/r/factorio/comments/54csz9/when_you_gotta_know_at_a_glance/)

----
^^Im ^^a ^^bot, ^^beep ^^boop ^^| ^^Downvote ^^to ^^remove ^^| [^^Contact ^^me](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=sneakpeekbot) ^^| [^^Info](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/) ^^| [^^Opt-out](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/comments/5lveo6/blacklist/)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo estic fent, però és complicadet! Maniré passant sempre que pugui i reconstruint. Crec que amb mantenir el que tenim està bé.
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Hola nois, estem intentant fer servir un script per dibuixar la senyera. Si el fem servir molts serem molt efectius, especialment durant la nit quan no ho podem controlar: https://www.reddit.com/r/catalonia/comments/635yxc/rplace_script_per_la_bandera/</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Se que arribo tard a la festa pero compteu amb mi! Visc als Estats Units (zona GMT -6), aixi que puc atacar en altres zones horaries</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Mucha suerte en chile también, debe ser duro vivir en el 3er mundo </utt><utt uid="1">Mucha suerte, debe ser duro vivir con un CI menor a 50 puntos. </utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Blog d[Alfred de Zayas](http://www.ohchr.org/EN/Issues/IntOrder/Pages/AlfreddeZayas.aspx), expert independent de lONU, [respecte Catalunya](https://dezayasalfred.wordpress.com/2017/09/23/media-statement-violation-of-the-right-of-self-determination-of-the-catalan-people/amp/):

The independent expert calls on Spain to suspend all measures of repression against the people of Catalonia and to cease interfering with the exercise of fundamental democratic rights, including the rights of freedom of expression, freedom of assembly and association, and the non-derogable right of the self-determination of all peoples.

-----------------------

Més declaracions (post-esdeveniments daquesta setmana) darreu del planeta [aquí](https://reddit.com/r/catalunya/comments/71k769/recull_de_declaracions_arreu_del_planeta_sobre/)</utt><utt uid="1">Com que les informacions han destar equilibrades, i com a contrapunt a aquest expert independent, vet aquí [aquest article](http://www.ecfr.eu/amp-article/commentary_three_myths_about_catalonias_independence_movement) postejat a /r/spain.

Conté arguments que intenten desmuntar els arguments en favor de la legalitat de lauto-determinació. Està escrit per lexpert no independent Francisco de Borja Lasheras, Head of the Madrid Office of the European Council on Foreign Relations.

No hi acabo destar dacord perquè el trobo absolutament partidista. Sobretot lúltim punt a on dona moltes voltes per bàsicament dir la llei és la llei i punt. Però penso que és més important informar-se dels punts febles que no fer un circlejerk amb les petites noticies que posen a Catalunya en una llum favorable.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Ara la merda ja està escampada, i el desmentiment no arribarà mai fora de Catalunya o fins i tot a moltes zones del país. Ens haurem de passar la vida enllaçant a articles com aquest cada vegada que algú faci servir la nota dexemple de per què els catalans no som capaços de governar-nos per nosaltres mateixos, que per què li donem les culpes de tot a Espanya quan els  daquí també són uns incompetents etc. etc.</utt><utt uid="1">Sempre ho pots enviar a /r/spain 

xD</utt><utt uid="2">Mare meva, cuanta merda que hi ha escrita alla... -_-</utt><utt uid="2">**Heres a sneak peek of /r/spain using the [top posts](https://np.reddit.com/r/spain/top/?sort=topt=year) of the year!**

\#1: [Lebanese army units fighting ISIS raise the Spanish flag on captured posts](https://www.lebarmy.gov.lb/en/content/salute-our-troops-fighting-isis-jurds-ras-baalbek-victims-spain-and-whole-world) | [18 comments](https://np.reddit.com/r/spain/comments/6urmgo/lebanese_army_units_fighting_isis_raise_the/)  
\#2: [Alhambra view](https://i.redd.it/qst7kqo603kz.jpg) | [15 comments](https://np.reddit.com/r/spain/comments/6y8n6j/alhambra_view/)  
\#3: [As a British man who has lived in Spain, I just wanted to send my love to all Spanish people today, I love you all!](https://np.reddit.com/r/spain/comments/6ugh0l/as_a_british_man_who_has_lived_in_spain_i_just/)

----
^^Im ^^a ^^bot, ^^beep ^^boop ^^| ^^Downvote ^^to ^^remove ^^| [^^Contact ^^me](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=sneakpeekbot) ^^| [^^Info](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/) ^^| [^^Opt-out](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/comments/6l7i0m/blacklist/)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Pues parece ser que esa agencia no informa/responde, como es normal, sobre comunicaciones marcadas como confidenciales. Así que es coherente lo que le han respondido a ese ciudadano.

http://www.elperiodico.com/es/politica/20170921/eeuu-no-puede-revelar-informacion-clasificada-6301054</utt><utt uid="1">Si estuviera clasificado lo diría en la respuesta, pero dicen que no les consta.

https://twitter.com/IvanLQF/status/910868451132149760</utt><utt uid="0">Si está clasificado dirían que no les consta, que es lo que han hecho. La documentación secreta o clasificada no existe a estos efectos. Pero es que es lo normal. NADIE firmaría ningún acuerdo de intercambio con una agencia que revelase ninguna información de este tipo que se considere clasificada, ni siquiera su existencia o fechas. Parece que queréis convertir esto en una conspiración o un asunto de credibilidad. 

Si DE VERDAD los mossos no hubieran recibido ninguna nota, ellos mismos (como autoridad policial) hubieran solicitado a ese organismo un documento (como el que ha solicitado esa persona) para desmentir la filtración y esa respuesta habría tenido muchísima más credibilidad. Vamos, eso hubiera hecho yo, así de fácil. En 24 horas lo hubieran resuelto, pero no lo hicieron.

Tendría todavía más gracia que esa noticia fuera un libelo y a ningún cargo dentro de los mossos se le hubiera ocurrido salir a desmentirla, con lo fácil que hubiera sido para ellos de ser falsa.</utt><utt uid="1">A ver, el [Freedom of Information Act](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/5/552) regula los casos en los que se debe informar que la información está clasificada, llamados exenciones, y los que la agencia consultada puede hacer ver que no les consta, las exclusiones.

https://www.hhs.gov/foia/exemptions-and-exclusions/index.html

Revisemos las exclusiones y comparémoslas con [la nota](http://estaticos.elperiodico.com/resources/jpg/7/7/1505995113977.jpg) y [la respuesta](https://pbs.twimg.com/media/DKMgzDWWAAIFGEl.jpg:large):

 The (c)(1) Exclusion

 Whenever a request involves access to records described in subsection (b)(7)(A) and

 a. the investigation or proceeding involves a possible violation of criminal law; and

 b. there is reason to believe that i. the subject of the investigation or proceeding is not aware of its pendency, and ii. disclosure of the existence of the records could reasonably be expected to interfere with enforcement proceedings, the agency may, during only such time as that circumstance continues, treat the records as not subject to the requirements of this section.

El (b)(7)(A) es la exención para

 (7) records or information compiled for law enforcement purposes, but only to the extent that the production of such law enforcement records or information (A) could reasonably be expected to interfere with enforcement proceedings

Si a los Mossos no les constaba la supuesta información de la nota,  ésta no habría interferido con ninguna investigación en curso. El supuesto no se aplica. Pasemos a la siguiente:

 The (c)(2) Exclusion

  Whenever informant records maintained by a criminal law enforcement agency under an informant’s name or personal identifier are requested by a third party according to the informant’s name or personal identifier, the agency may treat the records as not subject to the requirements of this section unless the informant’s status as an informant has been officially confirmed.

La información la habría pasado el NCTC; el tercero, los Mossos, no habría solicitado nada. El supuesto no se aplica. Y la última:

 The (c)(3) Exclusion

 (3) Whenever a request is made which involves access to records maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation pertaining to foreign intelligence or counterintelligence, or international terrorism, and the existence of the records is classified information as provided in subsection (b)(1), the Bureau may, as long as the existence of the records remains classified information, treat the records as not subject to the requirements of this section.

El (b)(1) es la exención para

 matters that are (1)(A) specifically authorized under criteria established by an Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy

O sea, que la información debe estar clasificada como secreta por Orden Ejecutiva del Presidente y solo si proviene del FBI, pero aún en caso que ellos fueran los que la encontraron (podría haber sido la CIA, o Seguridad Nacional, o vete a saber) ésta ya estaba en manos del NCTC y por tanto fuera de los límites de la exclusión.

¿Que por qué los Mossos no han pedido el documento, que se ve que ha tardado semanas en ser procesado y respondido, y perdido el tiempo revisando que no les hayan ocultado nada como acabo de hacer yo? A saber. A lo mejor no tienen a un experto en relaciones internacionales y derecho estadounidense que les asesore sobre el tema. A ver cómo reaccionan a partir de mañana.</utt><utt uid="0">Puede que me equivoque (el documento es lioso como el sólo) pero la 1-A parece un cajón de sastre. Vamos que si tienen una orden ejecutiva para no revelar determinados asuntos, tampoco entraría. Aunque igual me he perdido.</utt><utt uid="1">Pienso igual, el 1A le da poder al presidente para decidir qué se revela y qué no. Supongo que se compensa con el hecho que en la Orden Ejecutiva tienen que constar los temas que no se hacen públicos y al menos una mínima explicación de por qué de cara a la opinión pública. Pero en todo caso eso da igual, si la información ya ha llegado a manos del NCTC no está protegida por ese artículo y en la respuesta a la petición están obligados a admitir si en algún momento la han enviado al CITCO o a los Mossos, aunque los detalles sean clasificados.</utt><utt uid="0">Pues si odo eso es así, cómo bien dices, la pelota está en el tejado de los Mossos. Ideologías aparte, parece lógico que si efectivamente la nota del periodico es un libelo, un cuerpo policial serio debería denunciarlo.</utt><utt uid="0">¿ Entonces por qué Trapero reconoció que sí recibieron el aviso ?</utt><utt uid="1">Porque [recibieron *un* aviso,](http://www.publico.es/uploads/2017/09/20/59c29bc7e53ca.jpg) pero [Público no se moja en qué agencia estadounidense lo envió](http://www.publico.es/politica/cloacas-interior-antiterrorismo-sigue-dando-cuentagotas-informaciones-mossos-d-esquadra.html), por lo que podría no ser el NCTC como afirmaba la nota de El Periódico, del que se enteraron en circunstancias que dejan bastante mal a las autoridades anti-terroristas del estado:

 Nuestro servicio ofrece nuestras sinceras condolencias y apoyo tras los atentados en Catalunya del 17 y 18 de agosto –reza el comienzo del informe–. Ofrecemos la siguiente información para ayudarles en sus evaluaciones:

 1. Anteriormente, nuestro servicio pasó información con respecto a información no corroborada de veracidad desconocida correspondiente a finales de mayo de 2017, indicando que el Estado Islámico de Irak y ash-Sham (ISIS) estaba presuntamente planeando cometer atentados no especificados durante el verano contra lugares turísticos concurridos en Barcelona, España, específicamente Las Ramblas. Una revisión adicional de nuestro servicio identificó a un tal Abu Khadijah al-Karbaluti como potencialmente responsable de estos ataques sin especificar que el ISIS planeaba.

 A. Nuestro servicio no cuenta con ninguna estimación de que esta versión estuviera relacionada con los recientes atentados del 17 de agosto de 2017 contra Las Ramblas ni ha descubierto información ninguna que vincule a Abu Khadijah al-Karbaluti con dicho ataque.

 En resumen, la inteligencia de EEUU se toma la molestia de comenzar su informe –muy técnico y de más de 1.300 palabras– desmintiendo que el atentado de Las Ramblas pudiera estar de alguna forma relacionado con la alerta genérica sobre amenaza terrorista a lugares turísticos que se transmitió a finales de mayo. Parece, pues, que hasta al espionaje estadounidense le ha molestado que se tratase de emplear ese aviso para desprestigiar a los Mossos, que por cierto siguen afirmando que tuvieron noticia de esa alerta genérica por una vía no oficial, pero no, en absoluto, mediante una comunicación directa a ellos por parte de la inteligencia de EEUU... algo que sin duda sería insólito y llamativo.

 Ahora bien, lo que llama incluso más la atención del documento enviado por el CITCO a los Mossos es que ha sido borrado todo el encabezamiento superior (la mitad del primer folio) para que la policía catalana no viese información relevante como el servicio de inteligencia concreta que lo envía, en qué fecha, a través de qué vía, etc. Algo que demuestra que el CITCO sigue dosificando cuidadosamente la información sobre lucha antiterrorista que comparte con los Mossos.

 Fuentes de los Mossos han asegurado a Público que, en el caso de la alerta genérica previa de la inteligencia de EEUU sobre Las Ramblas, no sólo no les fue revelada en la Junta de Seguridad a la que asistieron en Madrid aquel mismo 25 de mayo, sino que tampoco les dijeron nada sobre ella en la reunión del 8 de junio (el 1 de junio hubo otra junta a la que no fueron invitados).

Es decir, todo lo contrario de lo que daba a entender la nota de El Periódico: ni los terroristas de la alerta estuvieron relacionados con los que planearon el atentado de Barcelona ni el CITCO intentó advertir a los Mossos pero éstos desoyeron sus avisos.</utt><utt uid="0">Y acabo de darme cuenta de que me falta un dato clave en todo esto... ¿ Qué pregunta exactamente hizo ese ciudadano ? En la respuesta no aparece la pregunta, sólo que no tienen información. Sin la copia de la pregunta, en realidad, no sabemos a qué se está respondiendo.</utt><utt uid="1">Lo dice claramente en el primer párrafo:

 you requested information on the communication on the communication between NCTC and Spanish CITCO agency, as well as communication between NCTC and the Catalan police.</utt><utt uid="2">Bueno, pues molt bé, pues adiós</utt><utt uid="1">No me creo una mierda de lo que diga el periódico</utt><utt uid="0">Estás en tu derecho, pero no confiaría en la eficacia de ningún organismo de este tipo que pudiera revelar cualquier información a cualquier ciudadano que les pregunte.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Gràcies! (Escrius millor que molts catalans! :) )</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Mapa original de TraceMedia, pots trobar el mapa interactiu, Terra Incognita, [aquí](http://www.tracemedia.co.uk/projects/terra/map/#lang=camap=languageloc=1)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">[Què collons fa en Josep allà? Ningú aquí pensa parlar del nord-coreà catalanòfil?](http://prntscr.com/g27v6p) Vull dir, conec al Cao de Benós aquest que de fet es polític a la RPDK, però un català? On, com, quan i qui?</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Oh gràcies! Molts catalanófils a Hamburg?

Mil gràcies als escriptors darticles de la viquipédia!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">No diries castellà (i espanyol) o sigui que no diguis català (i valencià) ja que és redundant i només ajuda a estendre la idea falsa de que són llengües diferents.

Tret daixò, em sembla molt interessant com hi ha més articles a França que a Espanya (a zones no catalanoparlants obvs). És molt curiós realment. També la zona de Hamburg em sembla curiosa. Upvote per a tu :)</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Quins pebrots... Sort de la majoria dusuaris a /r/europe que veuen que el que diu no té cap mena de sentit :D</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Forocoches es una mala imitació de 4chan. Un quiero y no puedo. Una de les comunitats més patètiques dinternet en la meva opinió.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El millor es vorel intentant defendres quan tot el mon esta diguent-li que el que diu no te ca ni peus.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El que sí que és xenofòbia és insinuar que els castellanoparlants no són capaços daprendre i fer servir el català.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Quina vergonya, i jo que pensava a que a forocoches hi havia gent amb una ment més oberta. </utt><utt uid="1">Home... Un o altre en deu haver... Però pel que he vist són més propers al *mesias Rivera*</utt><utt uid="0"> u haver... Però pel que he vist són més propers al mesias Rivera

no es volen pasar de la ralla i anar cap el feixisme extrem eh ;)</utt><utt uid="2">jojojo no passar-se de la ratlla aquesta ha sigut bona, mha fet gràcia </utt><utt uid="2">La rave extrema xD</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Really interesting doc, thanks for sharing it!</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Que no sen confii ningu que ja sabem tots que els que fan mes soroll son els dun bandol.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">La llàstima és que al 100% de la població li agrada mentir en enquestes :P Però com a indepe que sóc són unes xifres que malegren</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">El País mestà furtant les meves comparatives de shitpost barat, sols que ho diuen seriosament. Ni tan sols han utilitzat [la imatge adient](https://okdiario.com/img/2017/04/27/maduro-estelada-cataluna-655x368.jpg).  

0/10 El País necessita aprendre de mi.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Això si que no mho esperaba, vatua lolla!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El tomàquet del pa amb tomàquet és daquells rallats i posat amb pinzell? Ho sembla si més no. Siusplau, fregueu els tomàquets, feu-ho per ells.</utt><utt uid="1">el teu nom dusuari és genial</utt><utt uid="1">Es fregat, tranquil. Mhi he fixat al buscar-ne fotos</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Mossos dEsquadra Pepe 😂</utt><utt uid="1">Dat boi*</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Segons l[Atles de la Nova Ruralitat](http://www.fmr.cat/atles/materials/atlesruralitat.pdf) de la *Fundació del Món Rural*

P.D. No em jutgeu per linsignificant, que no lhe fet jo! :P</utt><utt uid="1">I lived in LEmporda last year. One of the best years of my life!
Que et vagi be from Washington DC!!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Interessant article 😁. Gràcies per compartir-lo!.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Visca la Catalunya Nord !</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Wut?</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Youre welcome. Now, as we allegorically say here, its time to keep the flame burning until the wind of history blows your sail again.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Thank you</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Aquí en el País Valencià también os apoyamos, pero lamentablemente en voz baja,aunque vamos en aumento. La gran mayoría está adormecida por el gran aparato mediático en vuestra contra, nos callan si debatimos o nos salen con los mismos argumentos absurdos como un loro. 

Cataláns y Valencians germans per sempre, algún día despertarem i tindrem la vostra valentía. 

Molt ánim y collons. 3 
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">¿Has pensado en una IPFS? Pedir que las compañias cierren el acceso pueden hacerlo, pero cerrarla no, y aún en el primer caso, puedes ignorar la prohibición con una connexión VPN.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">I consider this part of a concerning wave of nationalism sweeping the world, from Turkey to Brexit to Trump. I understand that there are some legitimate grievances buried in some of the pretty absurd rhetoric, but I dont think your political leaders have adequately explained the potential consequences of unilateral independence. </utt><utt uid="1">The whole idea seems to be to confuse. Seems like the focus is to convince the Catalan population that this referendum is actually democratic so they will go to vote to an illegal event, maybe get in trouble and scalate the conflict further. The problem for some people like me is that there doesnt seem to be actionable, thought-out steps to do after we achieve independance. There is no measure on how much we are going to lose either. They dont care if we get poorer, which is interesting when one of the arguments is that the Spanish government is getting a big chunk of money from what we produce. All of these would be negative points to get independant, so thats why they are hiding it. It is mostly some sympathists that are trying to reverse engineer how much it would cost, but the Parlament are the only ones that actually know for sure. </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El fanatisme es basa en la intransigència, en la fé cega en una ideologia sense cap mena de crítica, **com ara subordinar la democràcia a la unidad de la patria**.

Defensar un referèndum per donar el poder, la lliure determinació a la gent, a Blanes, Sort, Edimburg o Arbela (que avui decideix el seu futur btw) independentment de la ideologia de cada un dels participants, és justament loposat al fanatisme, ja que lautocrítica hi prima.

Veig que ets molt de titllar els catalans de fanàtics, feixistes, etc. Però pel que veig no saps que vol dir cap daquests termes.</utt><utt uid="1">Palabras vacías. Si es ilegal, es y será ilegal hasta que se modifique la constitución. 

Mientras tanto, los independentistas estarán transigiendo la ley. 

...Y sin ley, no hay democracia 

Todo lo demás es una monserga, y ya cansa lo pesaditos que estáis los 4 radicales. A ver si trabajáis algo ya joder, que los pobres españoles tenemos que comer xD </utt><utt uid="0">Beautiful, **que collons té a veure el fanatisme amb la legalitat?** No saps ni que dius... En sèrio, quina edat tens?

Btw, la legislació no fa la democràcia, Arabia Saudí té una legislació. És democràtica? **La democràcia la fa la gent exercint el poder**. Punt.

P.D. **Sí que és legal**, al menys llegeix-te aquesta constitució que tant defenses:

[Spanish Constitution](http://www.congreso.es/portal/page/portal/Congreso/Congreso/Hist_Normas/Norm/const_espa_texto_ingles_0.pdf):

**Article 10.2**:

 Provisions relating to the fundamental rights and liberties recognised by the Constitution shall be construed in conformity with the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and international treaties and agreements thereon ratified by Spain.

**Article 96.1**:

 Validly concluded international treaties [...] shall be part of the internal legal system. Their provisions may only be repealed, amended or suspended in the manner provided for in the treaties themselves or in accordance with the general rules of international law. [BOE 1977/10733](https://www.boe.es/buscar/doc.php?id=BOE-A-1977-10733) (Spains State Laws Publications Agency): The King signing and ratifying the **international covenant on civil and political rights**, which [says](http://www.ohchr.org/EN/ProfessionalInterest/Pages/CCPR.aspx):  PART I Article 1 1. All peoples have the right of self-determination. By virtue of that right they freely determine their political status and freely pursue their economic, social and cultural development. 

------------------------------ 

 3. The States Parties to the present Covenant, including those having responsibility for the administration of Non-Self-Governing and Trust Territories, shall promote the realization of the right of self-determination, and shall respect that right, in conformity with the provisions of the Charter of the United Nations.</utt><utt uid="1">Falso. 

Repásate la constitución en su totalidad y no me copies aquí solo los artículos que mejor respalden tus pobres argumentos separatistas. 

Yo alucino de verdad. Pero de verdad te piensas que vas a engañar a alguien con trucos de trilero? Para eso vete al circo. 

Por cierto, es ilegal al 100%, y me baso en la sentencia del Tribunal Constitucional Español (que algo sobre legalidad constitucional sabrán digo yo)

Zas en toda la boca. 

Un besiño y a la cama pequeño duende revolucionario </utt><utt uid="0">How is it false? I encourage you to learn some basis of law and to then check the articulate of your beloved constitution. Constitution that you havent even read.

Mind linking me the resolution of the Constitutional Court (thru BOE, not media propaganda, I see you coming). Im waiting.

 Zas en toda la boca. 

Oh! How mature of you. Seriously asking, how old are you? You act like a kid.

P.S. the Spainish governament is the first one not following your beloved constitution. And again, you cant even make autcritic out of it. Sounds like way closer to fanatism than the ones you accused earlier of it 🤔</utt><utt uid="2">Honestly, all of the spanish anti catalonian commenters I have seen on this sub seem neurotic adolescents with personality disorder judging the way they present their arguments with.</utt><utt uid="3">Pretty much that... </utt><utt uid="0">I doubt its more than one or two kids though. Most look like alternative accounts.</utt><utt uid="2">Y ojalá que la revuelta de las primaveras árabes se diera en las aulas, y que vea toda España como Occidente se dedica a capar a los que piensan con autonomía con agencias de periodismo completamente limitantes e incapacitantes para el raciocinio crítico.  De verdad telodigo. Para mí los nacionalismos son antinaturales.

/r/naturalscriptlang</utt><utt uid="2">No soy independentista, pero viendo el royo que se llevan en Madrid, yo prefiero un gobierno más pequeño. Porque si la globalización va a servir para mantenernos desinformados y separados, compartimentados e impotentemente sometidos a los gustos de 4 pro-élite, prefiero formar parte de una población de 7 millones con la que se puede hablar, que una de 47 millones con la que no.</utt><utt uid="1">Lo que tú prefieras me parece muy bien. Celebremos un referéndum donde todos podamos votar sobre el futuro de nuestro país.

“Todos”</utt><utt uid="2">Ah pues sí vale loco, votemos 50 el sometimiento de 10 para la serviud común. Quizá nos sorprendamos de la madurez de los 40 restantes. Y escudémonos en una ley que violamos cuando nos interesa. BITCH, PLEASE.</utt><utt uid="1">Estas para el manicomio. Supongo que cantar el mantra independentistas desde la guardería le acaba reblandeciendo la sesera a cualquiera. 

Pero una cosa puede quedarte nítida. La soberanía nacional no la van a romper 4 gatos cuperos antisistema. Y no te lleves a engaño, la gran mayoría de los catalanes (entre los cuales me incluyo) no queremos saber nada de la independencia.

Mas trabajar y menos hacer el payaso. </utt><utt uid="2">Perdona. Matemáticas, ¿recuerdas?

¿Por qué 40 tienen que decidir el destino de 7?

Bueno, hay gente pro-esclavitud. Luego están los que piensan y sienten.

¿En qué grupo dices qué estás? Te repito que me parecen un insulto a a inteligencia y un engaño de las élites los nacionalismos. Son palabras, organizaciones, grupos de gentes,... pero nos podemos reproducir igual con un indígena american@... no me veo diferente más que en minucias superficiales. No hay España y Cataluña. Sí hay, no obstante, el lenguaje español y el catalán: eso sí es una diferencia natural en el cerebro, ojo. Pero qué va, yo me siento sirio también. Y afgano, y turco, y ruso... pero los medios de comunicación se EMPEÑAN en hacerme pensar otra cosa.

DESPIERTE, sólo quiero un mundo mejor.</utt><utt uid="1">Yo quiero lo mismo. Pero unidos y en paz. </utt><utt uid="2">Si de verdad quieres paz, no permitas a tu presidente del gobierno pactar estrategias geopolíticas con Mr. Trump, que se mete en guerras que no existían, no permitas a tu Rey Don Felipe vender armas a los países proveedores de armas de los terroristas, no permitas a tu gobierno dificultar las energías renovables domésticas ni la educación online libre y 100% gratuita. No permitas que haya homeless. Si no lo haces, probablemente no puedo compartir tu plan de paz y mundo mejor.</utt><utt uid="2">Perdona si te molestó mi forma de hablar.

Es pueril pensar que 40 personas se van a preocupar por las otras 10 del grupo en un sistema en el que:

8 PUÑETERAS PERSONAS TIENEN EL MISMO PATRIMONIO QUE MEDIA HUMANIDAD.

Yo estaré para el manicomio.

Para mí el manicomio es esto directamente.

PD: te listo las veces que me han negado trabajar? Todo porque ciegos conformistas aceptan que las élites nos traten como ganado.

PD2: tú qué sabes si trabajo o no, a lo mejor soy más útil que tú en la sociedad

PD3: perdona de nuevo, no quiero ofenderte, me jode que te traten como ganado.</utt><utt uid="2">https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=eNQTZ_lxLXs

Este es el tipo de mantras que me influencian, por cierto, y no lo que me dicen en las noticias.

No me malinterpretes. El lavado de cerebro mediático es... cómo decirte... casi inevitable. Y si te sales, pam!  Que si loco, que si manicomio, que si jipi-come-hierba... en fin. Mucha paciencia es lo que hay que tener en el lado de la cordura social.</utt><utt uid="1">Tu deja manipularte más. Que lo siguiente son montar checas en bcn. Que paciencia dios. Nada, a repetir la historia otra vez, a falta de una, 2!

Eso quieres? Luego no llores. </utt><utt uid="2">No si los que estamos en el lado de los pobres estamos acostumbrados a llorar.

Tú tranqui, la historia la cambiamos en esta generación, de nosotros no pasa la subnormalidad de los elitismos vacíos estos. Tú ocúpate de no traficar con armas y de no privatizar la educación, que tratar con desinformados siempre es más difícil, pero si jugamos a poner las cosas chungas para la plebe, es lo que pasa.</utt><utt uid="1">Pero que cantidad de memeces sueltas chico. Anda échate una siesta que falta te hace. 

Tu generación como mucho cambiará la foto de perfil del Facebook, no vale para otra cosa y mucho menos como para algo tan crudo como una revolución totalitaria. 

Adeu </utt><utt uid="2">Jajaja bueno, esto ya lo iremos viendo, la gente crece respetando más a los pobres que a los ricos.

De momento ya se están rompiendo los esquemas de las sociedades feudales peperas. Veremos cómo van siguiendo las cosas.

</utt><utt uid="1">Lo tuyo es más grave de lo que parece en un inicio. Viendo el nivel friki que esto alcanza veo posibilidades para una nueva peli de Torrente. Gracias por amenizarme el ratin 

Deu!</utt><utt uid="2">Sí, espero que te haya sentado bien. Los pobres somos así, complacientes, serviciales.

De nada chato. Que vaya bien.</utt><utt uid="3">Tienes razón, votemos todos, así de verá por que partes España está rota, pero no es solo Cataluña, ellos son lo que ahora tienen huevos y luchan contra lo que creen injusto. </utt><utt uid="1">Si cualquiera pudiese luchar por lo que “cree justo” sin atenerse a las leyes nadie podría dormir tranquilo en este país. 

El respeto a la ley y sus tribunales es lo único que garantiza que todos disfrutemos de un estado de derecho. Cualquier otra cosa es retroceder en el pasado (la ley del más fuerte)

Cordura por favor, una cosa es la épica y la retórica indepe y otra es la realidad.</utt><utt uid="3">Claro, porque los franceses no lo hicieron, ni los americanos, ni... medio mundo básicamente, y también fueron actos ilegales con opiniones a favor y en contra. Pero bueno, ya vemos que países funcionan bien y cuáles no. </utt><utt uid="2">Pero tío, que también es cosa de la Constitución que TODO EL MUNDO MERECE UNA CASA. Y paséate por Barcelona por la noche.

/r/homelessfan

</utt><utt uid="2">Jajajajajajajaja vete a tomar el aire o algo que se te suben los colores </utt><utt uid="2">**Heres a sneak peek of /r/homelessfan using the [top posts](https://np.reddit.com/r/homelessfan/top/?sort=topt=all) of all time!**

\#1: [What do you see, when you come across a homeless??](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NEtfqrHLjPA) | [1 comment](https://np.reddit.com/r/homelessfan/comments/6zp41s/what_do_you_see_when_you_come_across_a_homeless/)  
\#2: [This society is sick. Elites are only psycopaths.](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oCJoptIuGlo) | [1 comment](https://np.reddit.com/r/homelessfan/comments/6zp04d/this_society_is_sick_elites_are_only_psycopaths/)  
\#3: [Tribute for homeless children](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AezxiThVmBEfeature=share) | [0 comments](https://np.reddit.com/r/homelessfan/comments/7198py/tribute_for_homeless_children/)

----
^^Im ^^a ^^bot, ^^beep ^^boop ^^| ^^Downvote ^^to ^^remove ^^| [^^Contact ^^me](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=sneakpeekbot) ^^| [^^Info](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/) ^^| [^^Opt-out](https://np.reddit.com/r/sneakpeekbot/comments/6l7i0m/blacklist/)</utt><utt uid="0">Sois una minoría de fanaticos. No estáis oprimidos, estáis como una chota.

Visca Cataluña libre (pero de gilipollas)

El discurso anti-independentista lo tolero. El discurso anti-voto1Oct lo tolero. Lo que no toleraré en este subreddit es que se acuse gilipollas y de estar como una chota cada dos por tres. Ayer o antes de ayer te avisé. Tu comentario ha sido eliminado. Este es el segundo aviso. Al tercero tomaré otro tipo de medidas.</utt><utt uid="1">Visca Cataluña!

Visca España!

El próximo domingo el mundo verá como se destapa la mentira independentista. Un golpe de estado, un atraco y una macro estafa a todos los catalanes. 

Por cierto ya están llegando los pro etarras a bcn. Disfrutad de vuestra democracia. 

Deu </utt><utt uid="0">Esto de lo que te hablo no es un debate político. Estás insultando a gente en este subreddit. Si no puedes ver más allá de la política y saltas al insulto llamando gilipollas este no es el sub adecuado para ti.</utt><utt uid="1">Aquí el insulto solo molesta cuando va en contra de los independentistas. Por lo tanto considero que estoy en mi pleno derecho de defenderme. Ojo, democráticamente y usando además mi derecho a la libre expresión.

Visca España y visca Cataluña 

No nos vais a secuestrar, el 2-0 seguiré siendo español y catalán. Ya basta de tonterías de becerro de monte. Que el mundo es muy grande para andar aún con las batallitas del abuelo comunista...</utt><utt uid="0"> Aquí el insulto solo molesta cuando va en contra de los independentistas.

No es verdad. Y te pediré por favor que me muestres comentarios contra no independentistas del tamaño de insultos y menosprecio que tu estás haciendo. Porque el único que ha tachado a todo el pueblo vasco responsable por las muertes de ETA, ha llamado gilipollas, fanático, estar como una chota y estar para el manicomio eres tú. 

Y estos ejemplos que he mencionado no son nada más que anécdotas dentro del conjunto de tu participación como semi-brigada en este sub. Dejate estar de viva España o viva Cataluña, cuando me pongo el flair de mod soy imparcial y me fijo en insultos y provocaciones. Sí, la situación está tensa en este sub y hay otras personas con comentarios que en otras situaciones intentaría controlar. Pero la mayor parte de la culpa es tu vocabulario, maneras y expresiones que desatan estos problemas. Si no me vas a responder con comentarios peores que lo que has posteado te recomiendo que ni te limites a responderme, porque lo entenderé como troleo y recibirás ban inmediato.

Un saludo,

Jop902</utt><utt uid="1">Tu dices ser el mod, comprueba tú mismo los insultos que me han proferido por defender la no-independencia. 

Mis comentarios han sido siempre en respuesta a otros insultos. 

Y por cierto, no se que hablas del pueblo Vasco. Yo me refiero a etarras, no a vascos normales y honrados. 

Esos etarras que hasta hace poco andaban asesinando y poniendo bombas por Cataluña y el resto de España. 

En fin, que viva España 🇪🇸!

Pd: Por cierto ánimo a todos los ciudadanos de bien asistir a la limpia de banderas y panfletos ilegales (hoy Las Corts han quedado libres de trapos ilegales)
</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Bon article!.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Això es posa interessant</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">**Catalunya aprova llei sobre el referèndum**

*El Parlament català lha aprovat amb 72 vots a favor, zero en contra i 12 abstencions. Madrid demana la intervenció del Tribunal Constitucional per bloquejar la consulta.*

El Parlament català ara podria votar la llei amb la qual es va a cridar per a l1 doctubre, el referèndum sobre la independència de Catalunya. Si, com és probable, la llei saprovés, l1 oct els catalans estan cridats a les urnes per respondre a una pregunta afilada: Vols que Catalunya esdevingui un estat independent en la forma de la República?.

Lacceleració cap a un vot que marcarà la història dEspanya ha arribat aquest matí quan la Mesa del Parlament de Catalunya ha acceptat la petició dels secessionistes, que tenen la majoria absoluta a lhemicicle, per a discutir i votar el mateix dia la llei de convocatòria del referèndum l1 doctubre. Aquesta decisió porta a la confrontació decisiva Catalunya amb el govern central. Loposició havia aconseguit assegurar la suspensió de la sessió dues vegades, creient que havia violacions de procediment. [...]

Madrid ha anunciat immediatament que soposarà per tots els mitjans al referèndum català. El president del Govern espanyol, Mariano Rajoy, ha ordenat interposar a lAdvocacia de lEstat una querella davant el Tribunal Constitucional per evitar que el Parlament català aprovi la llei de convocatòria dun referèndum que posaria en risc la indivisibilitat dEspanya consagrada a la Constitució. El primer ministre també va demanar a la consulta per determinar la responsabilitat penal del president de Parlament, Carme Forcadell, que va autoritzar lexamen de la llei.

La fiscalia espanyola ha anunciat que denunciaran el president del Parlament, acusat de desobediència, al Tribunal Constitucional de Madrid juntament amb Carme Forcadell i els membres la Mesa que han votat sí a llei de convocatòria del referèndum. 

El president del Parlament català,  en resposta a la iniciativa de Rajoy, ha demanat la inhabilitació de 12 dels jutges espanyols del Tribunal Constitucional per falta dimparcialitat i shan convertit en una extensió del govern de Madrid. La Cort espanyola ha rebutjat fins ara, en apel·lació pel govern central, totes les iniciatives catalanes cap a la independència.</utt><utt uid="0">Algunes altres fonts:

- **Reuters**: [Catalan parliament approves law to call referendum on independence](http://www.reuters.com/article/us-spain-politics-catalonia/catalan-parliament-approves-law-to-call-referendum-on-independence-idUSKCN1BH0QS?feedType=RSSfeedName=worldNewsutm_source=Twitterutm_medium=Socialutm_campaign=Feed%3A+Reuters%2FworldNews+%28Reuters+World+News%29)

- **South China Morning Post**: [Catalonia on collision course with Madrid over independence vote](http://www.scmp.com/news/world/europe/article/2110058/catalonia-collision-course-madrid-over-independence-vote?utm_source=t.coutm_medium=referral)

- **The New York Times**: [Catalan Parliament Paves the Way for Independence Vote](https://www.nytimes.com/aponline/2017/09/06/world/europe/ap-eu-spain-catalonia.html?smid=tw-share)

- **BBC**_ [Catalonia parliament approves independence referendum](http://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-41177428?partner=skygrid)

- **La stampa**: [La Catalogna proclama il referendum. Rajoy promette: conseguenze penali](http://www.lastampa.it/2017/09/06/esteri/catalogna-il-parlamento-vota-la-legge-del-referendum-indipendentista-f4JW7hdPvb9rR8f7gJP0jN/pagina.html)

- **Euronews**: [The Catalan parliament approves a law to call a referendum on October 1 on independence from Spain](http://www.euronews.com/2017/09/06/the-catalan-parliament-approves-a-law-to-call-a-referendum-on-october-1-on-independence-from-spain)

- **Financial Times**: [Catalonia passes bill for vote on independence from Spain](https://www.ft.com/content/91c176e6-92e2-11e7-bdfa-eda243196c2c)

- **The Wall Street Journal**: [Spain Moves to Block Catalonia Referendum on Independence](https://www.wsj.com/articles/spain-moves-to-block-catalonia-referendum-on-independence-1504720258)

- **Berlingske**: [Et Danmark ved Middelhavets bred](https://www.b.dk/globalt/et-danmark-ved-middelhavets-bred?referrer=RSS)

- **Mail One**: The Latest: Catalan lawmakers make way for independence vote](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/wires/ap/article-4857384/The-Latest-Catalan-lawmakers-debate-independence-vote.html)

- **La Reppubblica**: [Spagna, la Catalogna approva la legge sul referendum sullindipendenza](http://www.repubblica.it/esteri/2017/09/06/news/catalogna_referendum_spagna_indipendenza_barcellona-174768594/?ref=RHPPLF-BH-I0-C4-P5-S1.4-T1)</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Au idò, que pagui les despeses.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Jo també hi era, amb samarreta de capgrossos...</utt><utt uid="1">Al 4d9f us he enganxat bé laleta. :D</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">La qualitat del telèfon no em dóna per gaire.
</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">TIL: Im Catalan and I didnt know this town, thanks! Its a cool name, no need to change it.</utt><utt uid="1">+1</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">You would probably have more luck in a subreddit other than /r/catalunya? Ive been there, though, and its a lovely town (only it seems that more cows live there than people :P )</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Transcendencia internacional. Doneu-li les gracies gracies al Rajoi :) </utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Brutal: Utilitzeu tambe el meu torrent per si tumben tot:

magnet:?xt=urn:btih:b8414ad66df5470a1a91148d9b471b8b1839bf33dn=referendum</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Me pregunto si este enlace se considera contenido de calidad, tal cual se cita en las normas del foro. </utt><utt uid="1">Votar és qualitat, sí. La llibertat dexpressió és qualitat, sí.</utt><utt uid="0">No me refería al contenido en sí, sino a utilizar el nombre de rajoy (que lo creas o no, no es santo de mi devoción)</utt><utt uid="1">Rajoy és la persona que ha bloquejat vàries pàgines web amb altres noms. És simplement un simbolisme.</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Hi estic molt dacord, i crec que també hauríem de fixar-nos a reparar els dos cors, el de (425, 725) i el de lestelada a (555,770)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo estic que no paro... Entre el cor, que els espanyols estan transformant en la seva bandera; els pixels sueltos a la bandera i la gent que toca el logo de factorio. 

Però estic prioritzant arreglar logo de factorio, que estaven abans i sestava parlant de fer front comú per arreglar la zona.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Si no volem atacar factorio podriem fer una senyera menys alta, igual dampla. Fem les barres menys amples cadascuna.just per sota de factorio.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ooops! Soc nova en aquest rotllo i ho acabo de veure. Soc culpable datacar el Factorio aquest. 

On voleu que ataqui? Ja estic pendent de la senyera i dels cors. Alguna cosa mes?

PD. Perdoneu que no tingui accents en aquest teclat</utt><utt uid="1">Entra en el nostre el discord que allà pactem organització, tot i que de moment toca mantenir els cors principalment.</utt><utt uid="2">Osti, ara vec que hi havia organització bestia...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">http://imgur.com/a/yTQxE

maco maco</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">QUI ÉS EL FACTORIO?</utt><utt uid="1">Un joc (que està en català diuen xD) https://www.reddit.com/r/factorio/</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Tot i no voler aquest Estat com a exemple crec que és una notícia interessant.</utt><utt uid="1">Its an example of EU states trying to play politics. Hungary very much resents feeling secondary to a Brussels dominated by German and wants greater national autonomoy for EU states. Catalan independence isnt necessarily of any particular interest to Hungary and Victor Orbán is no champion of minorities, but this offers an opportunity to voice a contrarian opinion to Brussels. Hungary has already hinted at trade deals with the UK directly (circumventing the EU). Hungarian support for Catalan EU membership and possible trade deals absent EU membership seem to be bargaining chips Hungary seems willing to play. Its just unfortunate that Viktor Orbán is also willing to be a bit fascist to maintain his popular support.</utt><utt uid="0">Res, recordar-te que dir el mateix que Juncker amb mitja setmana de diferència poc en té en mantenir un posicionament contrari.</utt><utt uid="2">Catalonia now has more international support, just yesterday Venezuelas president Nicolas Maduro said Rajoy was a dictator. No joke !

Thats two authoritarian leaders who support catalan separatism so far, I wonder why the democrats are so silent. Maybe they dont like when un-democratic things happen ?</utt><utt uid="2">Greater autonomy? What else would they want? I think Orban just doesnt want anyone looking over his shoulders regarding fundamental rights.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">The far right of Europe supports the Catalonia referendum. Lovely. Birds of a feather, eh?</utt><utt uid="1">And the right, and the center, and the left, and the farleft...</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Ai iceta....</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Molt bon article, fa un bon tl;dr de la llei. Recomano molt la lectura completa, pero un TL;DR del article:

1. Aquesta llei nomes aplica si guanya el si al 1-O
2. Tribunal suprem sense sala militar, i el jutge designat pel parlament en comptes de lexecutiu
3. Hi ha un article que preveu anular casos instruits desde tribunals espanyols per haver defensat lindependència o la república.
4. El president pasarà a ser cap destat temporalment mentre es constitueixi la república.
5. Tots els funcionaris mantenen la seva plaça i el seu sou. Inclus la gent que treballa per infraestructures del estat espanyol (i.e. Hisenda)
6. El castellà serà llengua cooficial, junt amb loccità i el català
7. Es permet la doble nacionalitat catalana i espanyola. Aconseguir la nacionalitat catalana es molt més fàcil (tot espanyol empadronat a catalunya abans del 2017 ho es directament, o si son empadronades durant 2 anys seguits o 5 anys per ciutadans estrangers)
8. El calendari preveu la constitució de la república en 1 any, fins al 1-O del 2018. Haurem de passar per les urnes 4 vegades en total: referèndum d’independència, eleccions constituents, referèndum de la constitució catalana i eleccions republicanes.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Subí esto pero no soy catalán y me pregunto qué tanta fuerza tendrán los movimientos independentistas en el parlamento catalán para aprobar esto, pero sobre todo, para llevarlo a cabo. Los problemas prácticos de una independencia no son menores.</utt><utt uid="1">En el parlamento hay mayoría absoluta con JxSI (62) y CUP (10), 72 de 135. En cuanto a la fuerza fáctica en las calles, lo veremos el 2O y en menor medida el 11S.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Spain/Catalonia have among the highest per capita number of police officer in the EU (considering Guardia Urbana, Mossos and Policia Nacional all to be police). Additional officers probably couldnt hurt, but this is more about the collaboration between the Spanish national police force and the Catalan regional forces. Or perhaps the division between them, of which both the ruling, conservative Partido Popular in Madrid and the ruling, pro-independence parties in Barcelona are both responsible.  

Making this into an issue of Catalan independence (either for or against) is distasteful and unnecessary. Obviously the vast majority of the world isnt fully informed of the internal issues of Spain/Catalonia, so getting offended because anti-ISIS forces in Lebanon only raised the Spanish flag and not the Catalan one as well seems ridiculous. Not to mention the international demographic of the victims. </utt><utt uid="1">I agree with the latter part of your comment but would just like to correct something.

Catalonia is owed a considerable amount of money from Spain for the Mossos as per an agreement signed in 2010. Multiple times they have asked the Spanish government for the owed money and there has been no response. This is not only to hire new Mossos (as you mentioned might not be as necessary) but also for equipment, salaries, etc. etc.

Yes, the lack of cooperation is a problem but the police has been used as a political tool by the PP for quite a while now and part of their conditions for cooperation between the two squads has been to rescind the debt (though not said explicitly) and follow exactly what the Guarda Civil and Policia Nacional agree on. The Catalan government officials have even attended summits as spectators but refuse to sign the agreement for this very reason.

Certainly some things could have been done by the Catalan government and Mossos to prevent the attack to some degree (like the usage of speed bumps in Les Rambles) but in terms of cooperation with the Spanish government their hands are tied as a matter of principle. The safety and security of the citizens should not be used as a political asset.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Relevant link (in spanish): 

http://www.bolsamania.com/noticias/politica/jane-cree-que-cataluna-esta-legitimada-para-convocar-nuevas-plazas-de-mossos--2725571.html</utt><utt uid="1">Very thought-provoking post, thank you</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Acabo de mirar-ho, i sí. Han posat el nom de lEstat rere cada flair que no posseeix un Estat, imagino que per a satisfer cert grups. Tot hi que encara hi pots posar el nom que vulguis al escollir la flair.

P.D: No esperis molt més dun sub racista a més no poder.</utt><utt uid="1">Doncs això no pot ser! Ens hem de queixar tots. Crec que també han eliminat les banderes independentistes catalanes, algú mho pot confirmar? Si es així ho trobo molt fort...

Jo utilitzava la senyera normal, que també me lhan canviat per una més cutre que es veu pitjor (és una com borrosa que ningú utilitzava). Tots els catalans que utilitzàvem la senyera, fèiem servir la mateixa i es veia perfecte. De veritat no entenc que coi han fet.

PD: sí, lo del nom del flair sé que el pots canviar. Però es que jo ja el tenia canviat per posar només Catalonia! I no magrada que me lhagin canviat així com així sense cap avís. I com té pinta que ho han fet amb tots els catalans, molts pot ser ni tan sols es donaran compte.</utt><utt uid="0"> Doncs això no pot ser! Ens hem de queixar tots

Si voleu, jo encantat. Ara bé, no esperis molt d r/europe.

 Crec que també han eliminat les banderes independentistes catalanes, algú mho pot confirmar?

En efecte! Eliminada (només hi havia lestelada blava) totalment!</utt><utt uid="2">Sí, no sé perquè putes canvien la senyera per una que és veu com es cul. No té cap lògica.</utt><utt uid="3">Com que no te cap lògica? I tant que en té, el donar-nos pel cul, que a r/europe és un esport olímpic</utt><utt uid="2">No esperes res dels mods de europe, ja ens coneixem de sobres quina actitud tenen davant de feixistes explícits i tota la colla de nazionalistes espanyols que hi ha. A ask europe he demanat diverses vegades el flair amb la senyera però directament mhan dit que no hi estan interessats. I a europe no han eliminat la senyera perquè han deixat totes les banderes de regions espanyoles, si no ja no hi estaria tampoc.

Jo ja els hi he enviat un missatge a ambdós grups de mods.</utt><utt uid="1">En canvi sembla que no han tocat res a lIlla de Man, Palestina, les regions italianes, Transsilvània, Ossètia del Sud, les províncies irlandeses ni Kosovo, entre daltres.

No sé quin criteri exacte estan usant. Suposo que cap.</utt><utt uid="0">Després he vist que ni el Kurdistan, ni les regions italianes... només alguns com Espanya, els Països Baixos i Suïssa si no mequivoco.</utt><utt uid="1">I just look at it, and yes. They put the name of the state after each flair that does not have a state, imagine that to satisfy certain groups. Everything that you can even put the name you want to choose flair.

--

It was actually done for consistency when dealing with several hundred flags. </utt><utt uid="0">Why was it done with some States such as Spain and Netherlands, though, and not others like Italy or the United Kingdom? Idk, personally it just seems a way to avoid constant reports from certain groups.</utt><utt uid="1">Because the updates are being gradually rolled out and arent all changed over yet. </utt><utt uid="1">P.D: No esperis molt més dun sub racista a més no poder.

/r/europe és, de tots els subreddits europeus, el més tolerant. Si no pots tolerar /r/europe, ni pensis anar a /r/europeannationalism.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">He parlat amb el mod /u/MarktpLatz i mha explicat el motiu...

Segons ell tenen masses flairs i estan arribant al límit, i com que hi ha països que no tenen la seva bandera i necessiten més espai han hagut deliminar les duplicades o unir les que sassemblen massa.

El problema (i que fa semblar tot plegat una mica ridícul) és que dóna la sensació que només ho han fet amb Catalunya. Per no parlar que lestelada de duplicat de la senyera no té res. Més ridícul quan veiem que Andalusia i Astúries per exemple tenen la seva bandera literalment DUPLICADA. I la seva no lhan tocat! I això passa amb moltes altres regions: North Brabant, Crimea, Gelderland....

Li he comentat una mica això, però no mha respost.</utt><utt uid="1">We havent done this only with Catalonia. We are just doing it case by case. Just yesterday I also merged a second Belarus flag and the Canary Islands flag. Its an ongoing process, and its done mostly manually.</utt><utt uid="0">Yeah I know, already being explained that. I just found curious the changes on the Catalan flag (poorer version on *senyera* and deleting the *estelada*) when there are sooo many duplicated flags that seems obvious one would start working first with them: Asturias, Andalusia, North Brabant, Crimea, Gelderland....

And well the fact nobody informed us and we just faced that. In my case, I found myself with a poor version of the Catalan flag and the (Spain) added on the description. I dont know, surprised me a bit. Maybe being informed before would have helped :) </utt><utt uid="2">Can at least the (Spain) thing be removed? This wasnt done on Polish, italian or brittish regional flags last time I checked for example. Whats the point of it then?</utt><utt uid="1">It wasnt done, but it will be. We didnt have all the answers beforehand, the flair list *is* evolving. A lot of other countries (e.g. Belgium, France) do follow the format Region (Country).

You can of course put any flair text you want - although we are probably going to do some kind of explanation in the future (because nobody can tell what the flags are supposed to be anyway).</utt><utt uid="1">Sorry, I went to sleep after I responded to you yesterday. 

Let me begin with stating that it is inaccurate that we only did it with catalonia. We did a handful of countries yesterday and we will continue to move on. Its just that the process takes some time. 

About the version of the flag - I am not personally responsible for the flairs on our team, Ill see what I can do. </utt><utt uid="2">Its your subreddit and you can eliminate flairs as you please, but why do you change the Senyera for a poorer version?, the previous was well done. Now is a flag with literally [two Spanish flags](http://i.imgur.com/JPzzkDE.png) inside, because yellow is not equal in all lines. I know its not your responsibility but its hard to find logic in that movement, it seems pure *trolling*. 

Thanks for answering anyway 😁.</utt><utt uid="1">I have fixed the Catalonia flag, it looks more like the old one (with the shine), i.e. 1 extra yellow line at the top and bottom. The old flag had a shine effect that Im removing from all flags (especially the French and the German ones were awful), so that theyre using the true colors.

Sadly, our flair system has flags 16x11 pixels (and it would be way too much work to change this), so the 9 lines of the Senyera (the 4 lines of the Crown of Aragon, and the 5 lines of the yellow background) cant mathematically fit any better in 11 pixels.

As to the general quality, you should see what happened to the [flag of Venice](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venice#/media/File:Flag_of_Republic_of_Venice.svg) 😐.

This is not trolling, BTW. Its an attempt to keep /r/europe as neutral as possible. Personally, I *do* support the independence of Catalonia (but I also support the independence of most regions, probably because I want Greece be less in disadvantage in the national scene 🙂)

Ive also been to Barcelona (and loved the city), and I even had a SEAT Ibiza for 11 years, if that counts for anything (yes, I know its a VW Polo in Spanish clothing).</utt><utt uid="2">Yes, I imagine it was probably not trolling, but the different yellow was curious at least. I understand now it was for technical reasons. And I appreciate that you recover the older version, which as you said is not perfect but is better in my opinion. 

Thanks gschizas for the quick answer and no, having a Seat doesnt Count xDD.
</utt><utt uid="1">Not even if my dad had a SEAT 124? (which was a FIAT in disguise, of course 🙂)</utt><utt uid="2">Well, a Seat 124 is a different story, wish I could have one :D.</utt><utt uid="2">I think flairs should be removed by usage. And both catalan flags are fairly popular I would say. I dont care much because I am banned from that sub anyways.</utt><utt uid="2">lol, de veritat? :O</utt><utt uid="2">yes, apparently fascist jokes arent okay</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Sincerament que posin *Spain* per defecte tant més, ho lleves i pus, però que llevin lEstelada quan és un flair que sutilitza MOLT més que altres no ho entenc (jo duc la Senyera), i que posin una Senyera més lletja tampoc.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Segur que això sha fet per motius tècnics? I no es podrien haver eliminat altres banderes que no sutilitzen?

No sé, em sembla una excusa molt pobra.</utt><utt uid="1">No pas. Han canviat les que els hi ha donat la real gana</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">És graciós perquè precisament jo fa molt temps que hi tinc Catalonia, not Spain i això no mho han canviat (només mhan tret lestelada). No sé si encara es pot però abans clicant damunt del text el podies personalitzar perquè digui el que vulguis.</utt><utt uid="1">Deu ser per això, perquè tenies lestelada! Jo tenia la senyera i com a text Catalonia. La sorpresa quan he entrat i veig la bandera versió cutre i que mhan afegit (Spain)... home doncs una mica troll semblava jaja

Però sí que es pot canviar. Jo he fet el missatge aquí per si algun català no shi ha fixat, que revisi si li han canviat el text.</utt><utt uid="1">Sí, encara es pot fer això.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">A mi també mha passat igual. He passat de tindre lestelada amb País Valencià a tindre la senyera i Spain.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Molt patètic, no hi havia cap necessitat</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo he emprat sempre la senyera per que és la bandera de la Catalunya estat, però em sembla indignant, en fi, ja podem suposat el que ha passat, com sempre, r/europe demostrant el nivell i les influencies.

x cert la senyera també lhan canviat i ara és una puta merda mal dibuixada</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">17 dies després, Regne Unit no ha patit aquest canvi

Edit: Ni Irlanda, ni Itàlia...</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Una llàstima, EPD.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Sap molt de greu que marxi gent abans dhora, i especialment amb una persona com el Carles, que aportava tant a tantes persones. DEP.</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">¡Qué bonito! :D</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">1. [Diputats del Parlament galès a favor del referèndum](https://twitter.com/SimonThomasAC/status/910567960548388865)

 Democracy and civil rights must be respected and the catalan people must be allowed to hold a peaceful, transparent and democratic consultation on their future.</utt><utt uid="0">Partits: **PLAID, LABOUR, UKIP i Independents**

Members signants:

- **Simon Thomas**

- **Leanne Wood** (Líder de *Plaid Cymru*)

- **Lee Waters**

- **Llyr Gruffudd**

- **Bethan Jenkins**

- **Sian Gwenllian**

- **Nathan Gill**

- **Dai Lloyd**

- **Adam Price**

- **Neil McEvoy**

- **Rhun ap Iorwerth**

- **Caroline Jhones**

- **Dafydd Elis Thomas**

- **Elin Jones**</utt><utt uid="1">You forgot [MP Neil Hamilton]( https://youtu.be/no9UvZSs0Ms), the political sleazebag and Nazi-saluting *allegedly* fascist leader of UKIP in Wales, giving his support just this Wednesday (the 20th). I guess when its time for nationalist politics everybody want to be part of the fun.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">2.- [LAll-Party Parlimentary group on Catalonia](https://www.appgcatalonia.org.uk/) (APPG for Catalonia):

This referendum was democratically agreed to by the Catalan Parliament. To attempt to impede or stop it through sanctions, criminal charges and direct action by the Spanish state is an affront to democracy [...] We call on the Spanish Government to allow this democratic test of Catalan opinion to go ahead on 1 October without further hindrance.</utt><utt uid="0">- **Hywel Williams**, Chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Catalonia (Plaid Cymru)
- **Deidre Brock** (SNP)
- **Douglas Chapman** (SNP)
- **Joanna Cherry** (SNP)
- **Ronnie Cowan** (SNP)
- **Martin Docherty-Hughes** (SNP)
- **Neil Gray** (SNP)
- **Drew Henry** (SNP)
- **Ben Lake** (Plaid Cymru)
- **Chris Law** (SNP)
- **Stewart McDonald** (SNP)
- **Angus B. MacNeil** (SNP)
- **Carol Monaghan** (SNP)
- **Gavin Newlands** (SNP)
- **Andrew Rosindell** (Partit Conservador)
- **Tommy Sheppard** (SNP)
- **Chris Stephens** (SNP)
- **Martin Vickers**  (Partit Conservador)

També hi ha tres membres de la Cambra dels Lords:

- **Lord Rennard** (Liberal Demòcrata)
- **Lord Berkeley** (Partit Laborista)
- **Lord Wiglet** (Plaid Cymru)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">3.- El diputat quebequès Xavier Barsalou-Duval demana que el Canadà [denunciï davant la ONU el règim de terror de lEstat Espanyol](http://lecontrecourant.ca/2017/09/21/catalogne-canada-refuse-de-condamner-repression-xavier-barsalou-duval/)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">4.- Diputats sards demanen al govern de lilla que [**imprimeixi i guardi butlletes pel referèndum català**](https://www.vilaweb.cat/noticies/diputats-sards-demanen-al-seu-govern-que-imprimeixin-i-guardin-les-butlletes-pel-referendum-catala/)</utt><utt uid="0">Partitis: **Recull de partits sobiranistes** del consell juntament amb **Forza Italia** i el **Partit Democràtic**.

--------------------------

Una **moció de suport** aprovada per unanimitat menys per dos consellers que no eren al parlament.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">5.- Edward Snowden titlla la repressió de lEstat Espanyol com [una vulneració de Drets Humans](https://twitter.com/Snowden/status/910882660960088065)</utt><utt uid="1">but the one Putin frienfly [sic] is Edward Snowden, not Assange.

Your words, not mine. </utt><utt uid="1">I thought you said he was a Russian pawn...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">6.- Diputats dEstònia [critiquen les accions del govern i demanen diàleg](https://www.vilaweb.cat/noticies/diputats-estonians-critiquen-el-cop-destat-i-demanen-dialeg-al-govern-espanyol/?preview_id=358009preview_nonce=ae257f2812_thumbnail_id=358025preview=true):

 We call on the Spanish Governament to start finaly a dialogue with the Catalan authorities and people in order to find a peaceful solution that is based on mutual respect.</utt><utt uid="0">Membres signants:

- **Artur Talvik**, president del *grup de suport a Catalunya*

- **Andres Ammas**

- **Krista Aru**

- **Erki Savisaar**

- **Helmut Hallemaa**</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">7.- Sturgeon [demana respecte a Espanya per lautodeterminació de Catalunya](https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=84v=3p3YQIVOFDo) en un ple al parlament escocès.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">8.- El president del Parlament flamenc [demana diàleg al govern Espanyol](http://www.knack.be/nieuws/wereld/bourgeois-oppert-internationale-bemiddeling-in-catalaanse-onafhankelijkheidskwestie/article-normal-903229.html)</utt><utt uid="0">Tota l*Nieuw-Vlaamse Alliantie* (N-VA) hi dona suport. Aquests en són alguns noms destacats **Helga Stevens** i **Mark Demesmaeker**</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">9.- LEuropean Free Alliance (EFA) [llança la campanya #HandsOffCatalonia en support als alcaldes catalans](http://www.e-f-a.org/news/news/?no_cache=1tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D=1081cHash=ad38182c2bb685eda8f88afd8125285b) i alhora [condemna la represió de lEstat espanyol](http://www.e-f-a.org/news/news/?no_cache=1tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D=1082cHash=7c8e1b399798ae380f8fb687eb8627a3)</utt><utt uid="0">LEFA és una agrupació de partits del Parlament europeu de partits nacionalistes, regionalistes, autonomistes i/o independentistes. *ERC*, l*SNP* i el Partit Occità (*PÒc*) en són alguns de destacats. - [Aquí](http://www.e-f-a.org/whos-who/member-parties/) un llistat complet.</utt><utt uid="1">14th of September was before this weeks acts. End of topic...?

 </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">10.- La *GUE/NGL* [demana a la UE que es posicioni sobre Catalunya](http://www.guengl.eu/news/article/gue-ngl-news/eu-must-take-a-stand-against-spanish-government-repression):

This is unacceptable in any democratic country

GUE/NGL also calls on the EU institutions to protect the fundamental rights of the Catalan people as European citizens and not be indifferent to the events happening in Catalonia</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">11.- Els Verds dEuropa [demanen diàleg a lEstat Espanyol](https://twitter.com/europeangreens/status/910772399062360064)

The European Green Party strongly disapproves the arrests within the democratic institutions in Catalonia.

the EU should try to intervene in order to ease the tensions</utt><utt uid="1">Collons i els verds daquí????</utt><utt uid="2">In the 2014 referendum they were Sí / No.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">12.- El grup parlamentari europeu *ALDE*, en el que conflueixen el PDeCAT i Cs,  ha publicat al seu web [una declaració sobre Catalunya demanant diàleg **a ambdues parts**](http://alde.eu/en/news/977-alde-statement/):

Equally it is the prerogative of all Member states to organise their internal constitutional and institutional orders as long as they respect the principles enshrined in the treaties. This also includes the principles set out in TUE Article 4.2.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">13.- Seán Crowe (del *Sinn Féin*) [crítica durament (i sense embuts) al govern espanyol](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IKFTfZjiHQofeature=youtu.be)

P.D: Contribuició du/Esbarzer</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Where are La Liga Norte, Maduro or the Hungarians? And Assange? Are you ashamed of the support the referendum is getting from fascists and dictators?</utt><utt uid="1">They arent from the date in question, if they say something again they will be posted again. Btw, Rajoy is beheaving **way more as a dictator** than Maduro.

This said, if you want to debate tag me on another thread, **Im trying to keep thos clean for parlimemt/political parties declarations**, thanks.</utt><utt uid="0">La Liga Norte is a political part.. Maduro is president of Venezuela and offered his support just days ago. Zoltán Kováks in the spokeman for the Hungarian prime minister and spoke only days ago. How should those 3 not be on your list? </utt><utt uid="1">La Liga Norte doesnt have it on their website, you shared a link to the fascist unionist party DNJ website. Maduros support waa way before this week, and Orban was before too.

Btw, **move the combo to another thread** thus is intended to work as a list. Want more added? Tell me (plus official links) on another thread and Ill add them.</utt><utt uid="0">Maduro criticized Rajoy on the 18th of September. Kovács spoke this Monday, and has since clarified that despite their support for Catalonia, it is an internal matter. But both definitely offered their support *this* week. </utt><utt uid="1">And 18th of september was before this week acts. **End of topic**.

Edit: You are blocked. Now go debate somewhere else.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">14.- El partit andorrà Socialdemocàcia i Progrés (SDP), ha [mostrat suport als catalans per decidir el seu futur i ha repudiat lactuació de lEstat Espanyol](https://www.elperiodic.ad/noticia/60078/sdp-contrari-als-atacs-a-catalunya)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">15.-L Internet Society [critica la censura dinternet](https://www.internetsociety.org/news/statements/2017/internet-society-statement-internet-blocking-measures-catalonia-spain/) i acaba amb la següent conclusió:

 We hope to see a return to free and unfiltered Internet in Catalonia in the near future and call on all parties to commit to upholding freedom of expression and dialogue in this challenging time.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">16.- Les joventuts de tots els partits de la cambra danesa menys *Konservativer* es reuneixen davant lembaixada espanyola a Copenhaguen per [solidartitzar-se amb Catalunya](https://www.vilaweb.cat/noticies/les-joventuts-de-tots-els-partits-de-dinamarca-tret-dels-conservadors-es-solidaritzen-amb-catalunya/)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">17.- El Moviment de Participació Popular dUrugai (MPP), el major partit d*FA*, [mostra la seva preocupació i solidaritat](https://twitter.com/MPP609/status/911003796255408129)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">18.- 48 eurodiputats de 6 grups parlamentaris [condemnem la repressió i demanem obrir diàleg](https://twitter.com/ramontremosa/status/911183170812416002)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">19.- [Comunicat de solidaritat](http://www.hdp.org.tr/en/english/statements/hdp-stands-with-the-people-of-catalonia/10912) del Partit Democràtic dels Pobles (HDP), tercer partit al parlament de Turquia, esquerres kurdes i turques.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">20.- [Comunicat](http://www.amnistiacatalunya.org/paginas/noticies/noticies/articulo/1-o-catalunya-autoritats-estatals-i-catalanes-han-de-garantir-drets-a-la-llibertat-dexpressio/) dAmnistia Internacional sobre Catalunya.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">21.- L[expert independent de la ONU](http://www.ohchr.org/EN/Issues/IntOrder/Pages/AlfreddeZayas.aspx), Alfred de Zayas fa una [dura declaració respecte Catalunya](https://dezayasalfred.wordpress.com/2017/09/23/media-statement-violation-of-the-right-of-self-determination-of-the-catalan-people/amp/):

The independent expert calls on Spain to suspend all measures of repression against the people of Catalonia and to cease interfering with the exercise of fundamental democratic rights, including the rights of freedom of expression, freedom of assembly and association, and the non-derogable right of the self-determination of all peoples.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">I mentrestant a Espanya [laudiència nacional es nega a jutjar la cúpula del *Banco España* y la CNMV pel cas Bankia](http://m.eldiario.es/economia/Audiencia-Nacional-Bankia-Espana-CNMV_0_686981415.html)...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">La típica notícia que no arribarà als mitjans espanyols.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Hi ha fonts fiables? No fem un CIA ara.</utt><utt uid="1">[Almenys un dels diputats que suposadament lhan signada està retuitejant la notícia](https://mobile.twitter.com/nvillumsen?lang=ca)</utt><utt uid="0">Gràcies!</utt><utt uid="1">Larticle ha estat fet a partir dun tuit den Carles Puigdemont, i més dun parlamentari danès ha repiulat la notícia, així que no ho sembla pas</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Ànims a tots i força al braç! 😁</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Autèntics cracks!</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">[On /u/raicopk oblida que una mostra de 1000 és insignificant comparada al cens total català que forma un aproximat de 5.5M](http://imgur.com/a/hPlrp)

[Kek.](http://www.apuntesmareaverde.org.es/grupos/mat/3eso/11_Estadistica.pdf)

Aquest és el meu subreddit favorit per quan necessito riurem. Ah, i abans que diguis que una mostra és una mostra, recorda que en 3r ESO se suposa que aprens que una mostra vàlida en aquests casos hauria de ser dalmenys un 10%. Ara a fer downvote perquè fa mal la veritat.</utt><utt uid="1">1000 individus en una població de 5,5 milions et dóna exactament el que diu a la fitxa de dades, 3% de marge derror amb un 95% de confiança. On collons than ensenyat estadística? Per a les eleccions estatunidenques, amb un cens de 100 i escatx milions delectors, es fan servir mostres de mida similar amb un marge derror més que acceptable. Si calgués preguntar al 10% de la població per fer un sondeig electoral no sen farien!</utt><utt uid="0">1000 individus en una població de 5,5 milions et dóna exactament el que diu a la fitxa de dades, 3% de marge derror amb un 95% de confiança. On collons than ensenyat estadística? Per a les eleccions estatunidenques, amb un cens de 100 i escatx milions delectors, es fan servir mostres de mida similar amb un marge derror més que acceptable. Si calgués preguntar al 10% de la població per fer un sondeig electoral no sen farien!

/u/esbarzer sap tant destadística que soblida que totes aquestes xifres són depenents de la mostra i que partint de que la mostra invalida la credibilitat de lenquesta no importa res més. El nivell de confiança, i el seu interval, són extrets de la mostra. Si la mostra és roïna, tot el que hagues extret no pot ser molt millor. Crec que no entens que el problema es que la mostra es de 1000/5500000. Això es gairebé un 0.02% del cens. Lopinió del 0.02% del cens es extremadament variable en la pràctica. Una mostra de 10.000-50.000 sería més acceptablem, tot i que encara seria 5%. 1000 sobre 5M es ridícul i hauries de poder veure per què, aquest és un petit estudi (no ho ha fet cap institució del govern) i els resultats són de petita aplicabilitat. I no oblides que els sondejos dels EUA també van dir que Clinton guanyaria ;)

Ah, i Esbarzer, amic meu, sols per si creus que aquest thread es molt seriós i sé que no pots veure la burla, et recordo:
visca ~~venezuela~~ Catalunya! Seig Heil!
</utt><utt uid="1">Descuida, tot això ho faig per refrescar el que vaig aprendre destadística a la uni. Amb una mica de sort aprendràs alguna cosa.

 /u/esbarzer sap tant destadística que soblida que totes aquestes xifres són depenents de la mostra i que partint de que la mostra invalida la credibilitat de lenquesta no importa res més.

En sé prou per saber que la mida de la població total és matemàticament irrellevant mentre, de fet, sigui ordres de magnitud més gran que la de lunivers de la mostra.  Té, llegeix sobre marges derror i intervals de confiança:

http://www.robertniles.com/stats/margin.shtml

http://math.arizona.edu/~jwatkins/505d/Lesson_12.pdf

Un vídeo que explica el mateix i introdueix el concepte de ponderació per a variables no aleatòries segons el segment de població:

https://www.scientificamerican.com/video/the-math-behind-the-polls/

Que a més, literalment tots els sondejos del món mundial treballen amb aquesta mida de mostra perquè fer-ne servir de més grans és una pèrdua de calers, la matemàtica demostra que el cost denquestar més persones es tradueix en un augment negligible de la confiança del resultat.

Sobre les últimes eleccions americanes, van complir la seva feina: Lerror entre les enquestes i la realitat va ser del 2%, menys encara en les de Five Thirty-Eight que eren les que jo seguia i ja li donaven a en Trump un 29% de probabilitats de guanyar. És un problema dun sistema de 50 jocs matemàtics de tot o res com el col·legi electoral, petites desviacions en el vot generen grans canvis.</utt><utt uid="0">Saps, sóc un shitposter dels pesats, però quan em paro a fer un argument seriós i sóc refutat puc donar-te la raó. Després dhaver revisat les fòrmules veig el sentit en el que originalment estaves dient. En vista daçò, puc veure el meu error en malinterpretar el fet que les xifres que vas mencionar són dependents de la mostra (que ho són, sols que la mostra de 1000 té una confiança i MDE independent de lunivers). Partint daçò tindré la maduresa dalmenys retractar-me en la primera posició seria que he adoptat dins daquest sub i de disculpar-me pels ad-homs. Amb aquesta base no queda res per a dubtar superficialment lestudi del enllaç. Estava convençut del que estava dient i estic disposat a retractar-me amb aquesta.

/u/raicopk perquè la refutació ha sigut pràcticament la mateixa i tota la resta que has volgut refutar dins dels meus comentaris no era argumentació.</utt><utt uid="2">Això és el miracle de nadal!!</utt><utt uid="0">Quan no faig shitposting, sí. Quan faig shitposting, no.</utt><utt uid="0">Diguem, però vés amb compte perquè al llarg de la meva història en Reddit no he rebut molts missatges que se suposa mhavien manat. Quan ho manes, respon i et diré si lhe rebut correctament.</utt><utt uid="1"> On /u/raicopk oblida que una mostra de 1000 és insignificant comparada al cens total català que forma un aproximat de 5.5M

Sen diu enquesta, guapo

 Aquest és el meu subreddit favorit. Ah, i abans que diguis que una mostra és una mostra, recorda que en 3r ESO se suposa que aprens que una mostra vàlida en aquests casos hauria de ser dalmenys un 10%. Ara a fer downvote perquè fa mal la veritat.

De verutat encara estàs trolejant? Noi, la teva vida deu ser trista, eh?</utt><utt uid="0">Sen diu enquesta, guapo

No. [La mostra és una part de lenquesta.](https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Muestra_estad%C3%ADstica) Quants anys tens i per què no saps res de matemàtiques de lESO? Ja sé que és molt demanar coneixements matemàtics dun independentista (recordatori que Oriol 16.000 milions que en realitat són 3 milions Junqueras existeix), però no tindre idea del que és una mostra... gloriosa educació, guapo.

De verutat encara estàs trolejant? Noi, la teva vida deu ser trista, eh?

En realitat tinc uns dies de res ara mateix perquè la meva agenda destiu no ha començat encara. Aquest sub és fantàstic quan mabelleix riurem, de debò. Magrada també com no pots negar que lenquesta està mal fonamentada. </utt><utt uid="1">Erm... Hola? Que no sigui una mostra representativa, com no ho són la gran majoria, no treu que segueixi sent una enquesta. Al menys llegeix-te el que enllaçes carinyu.

No, si els 16.000 [són comptes de la Junta dExtremadura](http://i.imgur.com/XFQuBo4.jpg), no den Junqueres😘</utt><utt uid="1">No li donis corda, la mostra és perfectament representativa.</utt><utt uid="0">Erm... Hola? Que no sigui una mostra representativa, com no ho són la gran majoria, no treu que segueixi sent una enquesta. Al menys llegeix-te el que enllaçes carinyu.

És una enquesta invàlida perquè la mostra no és suficient  com per a extraure conclusions sòlides. Coses que tensenyen a 3r de lESO, una altra vegada. No ho sé, sembla que manques coneixements bàsics, pero ei, visca ~~venezuela~~ Catalunya! Seig Heil!

No, si els 16.000 són comptes de la Junta dExtremadura, no den Junqueres😘

Això volgueres:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YUo9GzSRIdY
</utt><utt uid="1">Com ja he dit, que no sigui una mostra representativa, no vol dir que no sigui vàlida. El ceo tampoc no és una mostra representativa. És que ni llegir-te el que enllaçes, mare meva...

I per cert, jo the donat un document oficial de la junta, si no et vols creure les seves resolucions, tu a la teva</utt><utt uid="0">Com ja he dit, que no sigui una mostra representativa, no vol dir que no sigui vàlida. El ceo tampoc no és una mostra representativa. És que ni llegir-te el que enllaçes, mare meva...

La mostra és de 1000/5500000, açò és de 0,018%. Això vol dir que de 44000 persones en consultaries 8. ¿Et sona vàlid? Petita mostra, petita aplicabilitat. El panorama del referèndum té una extensió gran, 5.5M de persones. No pots aplicar una conclusió extreta duna mostra tan petita. Una mostra més vàlida seria de 10.000-50.000 (que encara no és molt gran, 5%). Aquest és un petit estudi que no té les dimensions mostràries suficients per a poder extraure el que pensen 5.5M de persones i si no ho entens, torna a lESO.

I per cert, jo the donat un document oficial de la junta, si no et vols creure les seves resolucions, tu a la teva

És gairebé místic com trobes una contradicció on no nhi ha. Jo (bromejo) que Junqueras va dir que *espanyansroba* 16 000 000 E, tu has demanat font, jo the donat un vídeo on Junqueras diu exactament açò.</utt><utt uid="1"> La mostra és de 1000/5500000, açò és de 0,018%. Això vol dir que de 44000 persones en consultaries 8. ¿Et sona vàlid? Petita mostra, petita aplicabilitat. El panorama del referèndum té una extensió gran, 5.5M de persones. No pots aplicar una conclusió extreta duna mostra tan petita. Una mostra més vàlida seria de 10.000-50.000 (per a grans estudis, grans mostres)

Sincerament, o ets molt mal troll o no ets més babau perquè no tentrenes. Les enquestes deleccions a Espanya, amb +40milions de ciutadans, es fan amb mostres similars, i el mateix per el RU, els EUA o la Xina, i tot hi així són vàlides.

I tros doca, lúnica conclusió serà el resultar del referèndum, no una enquesta.

 (bromejo) que Junqueras va dir que *espanyansroba* 16 000 000 E, tu has demanat font, jo the donat un vídeo on Junqueras diu exactament açò.

Aix aquesta comprensió lectora... No he dit pas que no ho digués, simplement que aquests nombres, que segons tu són falsos,  són comptes de la Junta dExtremadura, i no dem Junqueras com abans has afirmat. Aveure si llegim més.</utt><utt uid="2">SECTION | CONTENT
:--|:--
Title | Oriol Junqueras conferencia; Espoli i crisi.
Description | Junqueras: és indigant que paguem el 24% dels impostos i només en rebem el 10%!. Amb Espanya mai ens en sortirem Els republicans presenten la campanya Prou Espoli, ara República Catalana i deixen petit el Centre Cívic de lEstació del Vendrell  Dimarts dia 10 de juliol a les 20 hores aprofitant les festes del pa beneit del Vendrell, Oriol Junqueras va visitar la capital del Baix Penedès i va exposar les dades de lespoli fiscal de Catalunya a la sala dactes del Centre Cívic de lEstació dav...
Length | 1:04:39

 

 
 
 
****
 
^(I am a bot, this is an auto-generated reply | )^[Info](https://www.reddit.com/u/video_descriptionbot) ^| ^[Feedback](https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=video_descriptionbotsubject=Feedback) ^| ^(Reply STOP to opt out permanently)</utt><utt uid="1">Qui et va ensenyar això del 10% a 3r. dESO et va enganyar molt. Lestadística no funciona així, és una mica més complicat i enlloc del món són necessàries mostres tan grans.</utt><utt uid="2">Nano que tu mai estudiat estadística més enllà de la ESO no vol dir que nosaltres tampoc. Quan no es coneix un tema sovint és millor callar, o com a mínim no atacar als que sí en sabem.</utt><utt uid="1">^(Hi, Im a bot for linking direct images of albums with only 1 image)

https://i.imgur.com/e9G0udj.png

^[Source](https://github.com/AUTplayed/imguralbumbot) ^| ^[Why?](https://github.com/AUTplayed/imguralbumbot/blob/master/README.md) ^| ^[Creator](https://np.reddit.com/user/AUTplayed/) ^| ^[ignoreme](https://np.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=imguralbumbotsubject=ignorememessage=ignoreme) ^| ^[deletthis](https://np.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=imguralbumbotsubject=delet%20thismessage=delet%20this%20dj2eng8) </utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Ostia jo mapunto a fer una </utt><utt uid="1">Quan vulgueu dieu i en fem una!</utt><utt uid="0">Envia un privat o algu i ho organitzem </utt><utt uid="1">Sip! Potser fer un grup/discord seria bona idea.

O simplement fer un post aqui dies abans amb el dia i lhora xq la gent shi apunti</utt><utt uid="0">Si es bona idea.  Per aquestes coses hauríem de decidir un dia(tipo diumenge tarda o aixis) i fer sessions de  2-3h que fer una partida en un dia es impossible  xdd.  </utt><utt uid="2">Ep, arribo tard, però a mi també minteressaria!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">[CORONA DARAGÓ stronk](https://imgur.com/a/tvuz9) </utt><utt uid="1">Ep! Pots jugar com Catalunya també (territori països catalans)!</utt><utt uid="0">Siiii! :-)</utt><utt uid="2">[Bitch please](http://imgur.com/a/Qx1wx) (un album vell que vaig penjar a /r/eu4 )</utt><utt uid="1">Malparit, macabes de costar 40€.</utt><utt uid="0">EU es €40? Espera per el Steam summer sale, amic👌👌</utt><utt uid="1">Però això implica que mhe desperar...</utt><utt uid="0">Si però llavors tens rebaixes de 80% de tots de EU4</utt><utt uid="1">Oooh està bé, a veure si aguanto.</utt><utt uid="0">Es possible el pròxim Steam Summer sale es en 8,5 setmanas 

http://whenisthenextsteamsale.com/</utt><utt uid="1">Alfons de trastamara es un pepino de general</utt><utt uid="0">[el perfect monarca no existeix](https://i.imgur.com/7VboWWo.png)...</utt><utt uid="1">Això és el que passa quan es casen entre cosins xxd
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">http://www.wingamestore.com/product/2912/Europa-Universalis-IV/
A 9.19 dólars

Per si algú sha dacabar de decidir. Jo sempre ho miro primer a isthereanydeal.com.

https://isthereanydeal.com/#/page:game/info?plain=europauniversalisiv
</utt><utt uid="1">Ostres, gran pàgina, no la coneixia! </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Quan tingui un PC decent...</utt><utt uid="1">La veritat és que no necessita un gran ordinador, ja que els gràfics tampoc són res de laltre món. Això sí, tardà 5 hores en carregar.

A steam pots veure els requisits mínims. Tret que tinguis una sandvitxeria amb Windows XP podràs jugar.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo el tinc! pero sóc realment mediocre</utt><utt uid="1">Haha. A això shi posa remei ràpidament! 😋</utt><utt uid="0">De fet tinc un amic youtuber graduat dhistòria que [en sap un niu](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z-0H5iEWocg) però tinc passa poca paciència per apendre hahah. Si voleu fer partida aviseu-me</utt><utt uid="1">Carai! Intenta destruir Castella amb Aragó per apendren! Potser això et dona la paciència necessària! 😋</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Fals, EUIV és un joc de gran contingut adicional. ;)</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Fet!</utt><utt uid="1">Moltes gràcies!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Fet :)</utt><utt uid="1">Gràcies:)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Comenteu per aqui quan acabeu l estudi! Un copy paste ja n hi ha prou! =P</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Molt bé, les coses que has enumerat semblen senzilles però tenen un impacte profund, bona sort!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El metode de Marie Kondo funciona prou bé pel que he sentit :)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Ànims! La uni és dura, que no pugui amb tu.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Intenta beure menys begudes amb sucre I més aigua és un bon repte</utt><utt uid="1">Gràcies pel comentari :) És una bona idea! </utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">:) feliç diada!!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona diada a tothom! Tot just arribo de la manifestació i això és impressionant! :-D</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Bona diada!

Visca Catalunya</utt></s><s></s><s><utt uid="0">Arribo tard per lo de la manifestació pero bona diada!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">La manifestació va ser espectacular (jo no hi vaig ser, massa lluny). Queda moltíssim per fer, però crec que anem per bon camí.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Lo diré en dos palabras: im-presionante

/joke

Aixo es dabans de la consti del 78, pero es algo molt significant. Rajoy repetint com un lloro que lautodeterminació no es dona enlloc ha quedat completament retratat. Al BOE dEspanya, queda al registre dun article que el reconeixia.</utt><utt uid="1">Però està firmat per en Joan Carles, no en Francesc</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Que nopines de la sentència?
</utt><utt uid="1">Home...Continua éssent un judici polític, i per tant, ho seguiria veient negatiu tant si sels hagués empresonat com si sels hagués absolt. Ara bé, si que crec que el TSJC ha estat com una mena de suavitzant entre Cat i el TC, tot i que dubto que el primer hagués gossat fer gaire més que el que ha fet el TSJC, sobretot ara que el procés ja ha cridat més que clarament latenció internacional.</utt><utt uid="0">Jo crec que la sentència  que ha estat la esperada ja que normalment el jutge no fa cas ni al fiscal ni a la defensa particular i busca un punt intermedi.</utt><utt uid="1">No busca pas un punt intermedi, jutja a partir de la legislació vigent el cas i tipifica en funció del delicte (o no). Ara bé, si és un judici polític, com és el cas, es pasa de la legislació a la valoració ideològica, quelcom que fins hi tot la constitució espanyola suposadament impedeix.
Però en cap cas un jutge (hipotèticament neutral) busca un terme entre lacusat i lacusant, sinó q es guia per altres raons.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Voleu una entrada des de la demarcació de Barcelona?</utt><utt uid="1">Ens agradaria molt :) </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">No sóc del territori que demaneu, però li diré a tothom a qui conegui de Lleida i Tarragona :D.</utt><utt uid="1">Moltes grácies</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Fet, des del Camp de Tarragona ;)</utt><utt uid="1">Moltes grácies</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Done from Tarragona! </utt><utt uid="1">Moltes grácies 

</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">bye bye, hasta otro ratito, eh?</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Inici de la campanya pel referèndum de part de Demòcrates de Catalunya (part del grup parlamentari JxSí), [aquí](https://youtu.be/wOxoqyFbA9s) podeu trobar el segon vídeo de la campanya.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Realment no costa gaire fer un vídeo així. Lestat espanyol ha deixat anar moltes perles per fer-nos marxar...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Tornar a sentir expressions com totalitari, nazionalista...

[Rellevant.](https://i.ytimg.com/vi/6NmABXZGtP0/maxresdefault.jpg)</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Al·lucinant, tota la transició va ser una estafa. Una constitució sense procés constituent. 

I ara els comuns demanen unes garanties indefinides quan la C78 no en té ni una. Ni una!</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Jo em trobo que els meus amics no tenen ni idea de com utilitzar el reddit i això els tira enrere. Clar està que són molt hàbils en qualsevol altra xarxa social.

Edit: A part de notícies, quin contingut és ladequat per /r/Catalunya ?</utt><utt uid="1"> A part de notícies, quin contingut és ladequat per /r/Catalunya ?

Tot el relacionat amb Catalunya i la resta dels Països Catalans.</utt><utt uid="0">De fet, ens podríem promocionar fent trobades.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Jo proposaria treballar els crossposts. 
potser fer petites traduccions o inclús TL;DR darticles que siguin interessants als comentaris i penjar-los a r/politic o r/worldnews.  </utt><utt uid="0">exemple:
http://www.reddit.com/r/funny/comments/2f8v05/overdoing_the_ice_bucket_challenge_crosspost_from/</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">El que hauríem de fer és introduir més gent dels Països Catalans a reddit. Jo no conec ningun rèdditor català (tampoc no és que conegui gaire gent que parli bé anglès, però), excepte jo.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Nois (i noies, si nhi ha), aqui en teniu un altre, de redditor catala</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Trobo que sí, que ara hi ha molt de contingut. Lo de lactivitat ja és més complicat, jo personalment no conec ningú que entri a reddit. També crec que lactivitat anirà apareixent sola a mida que els continguts vagin donant de si i també quan comencem a posar contiguts originals, que al menys per part meva, no soc gaire de comentar notícies. </utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Crec que Reddit és una eina que no sutilitza gaire a Catalunya - però aixó no és cap problema! A Catalunya ja nhi ha prou de comunicació entre el poble, coordinació a través daltres xarxes socials més majoritaries (Twitter, Facebook...) i boca a boca. Crec que hauriem dutilitzar aquest reddit com a un punt de projecció cap a la comunitat internacional, i intentar fer la situació viral a partir de pàgines con imgur.com... Jo sóc bilingüe en anglès i mofereixo voluntaria si necessiteu qualsevol traducció.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Un altre acudit que haurem de canviar...  
- Pare, puc anar al circu?  
- No fill, qui vulgui veuret que vingui a casa.  
  
vs.  
  
- No fill, ara no deixen entrar animals.  
  
Meh...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Així dentrada no magrada gaire la notícia, però confesso que no domino gaire sobre aquest tema. Suposo que hi ha casos i casos, però no veig perquè no es poden tenir els animals de circ ben cuidats.</utt><utt uid="1">Li prego que em mostris un exemple de un circ ben cuidat. Llavors, i només llavors podem tenir un diàleg sobre això.
</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Els animals de circ prohibiran utilitzar catalunya</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">*Polònia</utt><utt uid="1">Aaaaaaaah, per fi! Sabia que no podia ser lúnic al que li molestava, però em feia cosa posar-ho perquè no és que magradin molt els grammar nazis :/</utt><utt uid="0">Jo també me nestic moltes vegades. Però he pensat que al subreddit de Catalunya havia de fer aquesta petita aportació. 

De fet no és cap crítica (trobo que laportació de gripaubabau és bona) i pot haver estat simplement un petit descuit, però penso que, de no ser-ho, no està de més assenyalar el petit error gramatical. A mi magrada que la gent mho faci, però entenc que a molta gent li pot molestar :)</utt><utt uid="2">Gràcies per la correcció. No és cap excusa però fa molt de temps que no escric amb català!</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Interessantíssim article. Intento compensar el mem de laltre dia...</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Què acabo de llegir? És real o _fanfiction_?</utt><utt uid="1">Jo crec que és real, i a més, veient la compenetració requerida per tres partits tant diferents, imprescindible.</utt><utt uid="0">Doncs si és real estic molt impressionat. La quantitat dhistòries que han succeït en secret fins ara sembla de pel·lícula</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Molt interessant. Gràcies per compartir.</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Sant Cugat de Mar.</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">It looks great! The divisions represent the diverse terrains? Im not sure of it. Can you explain it to me?</utt><utt uid="1">Climates</utt><utt uid="1">Thank you very much! :)

[This](https://ca.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clima_de_Catalunya#/media/File:Mapa_climatic_de_Catalunya.svg) is the source. It basically classifies the various types of climate in Catalunya, but simplified.

Shouldve put that in the title. Apologies for any confusion, mate!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Its a very interesting map, although Sant Cugat is misplaced.</utt><utt uid="1">Why add Sant Cugat to a map that only contains capitals and if you do, why do it wrong? Takes away all credibility.</utt><utt uid="2">Un amor perdut... 😢

I did it on purpose, because otherwise the border would cross the name of Sant Cugat itself, which looks even worse IMHO</utt><utt uid="2">Youre right. I did that on purpose, because otherwise, one of the black lines would cross the name of the city, which looked worse than this IMHO</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">*reverència*</utt><utt uid="1">Gràcies i molt amable, amic! :D</utt><utt uid="0">Has pensat a posar-lo a r/MapPorn ? :D</utt><utt uid="1">Hmmm, no ho he pensat. Gràcies per la recomanació! :-)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">My girlfriend does graphic design for a living, and last time I did some major work on /r/Tarragona, I included some graphics, some of which I made myself.

I created this one, but I dont think I ever used it online. Its [a climate map of Catalunya](https://ca.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clima_de_Catalunya#/media/File:Mapa_climatic_de_Catalunya.svg). I was inflating my own ego when I said that I was pretty proud on this one.

Thought Id share it here. Might do some more maps in the coming months of cities in Catalunya, or maybe Spain. Was hoping to indulge myself in some compliments of you guys too.

I took some artistic liberty when it came to the placement of the cities dots and names, in order to make it look better.

I definitely think its one of my better works!

* [Source](https://ca.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clima_de_Catalunya#/media/File:Mapa_climatic_de_Catalunya.svg) 
* Program: Vectr (free)</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">Què té despecial Sant Cugat?</utt><utt uid="1">Un amor perdut... 😢</utt><utt uid="0">Benvingut al club, xato. Cagun Sant Cugat i les pixapines</utt><utt uid="1">No ho entenc molt bé, però gràcies, amic. :)</utt></s></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Not sure about the voiceover at the end, sounds like he thought it was for a horror movie or something!</utt></s><s><utt uid="0">I want to move to Catalunya myself, also in a few years. Catalan is definitely difficult, but to me it generally looks like Castilian.

I think this is a somewhat controversial topic, but Valencia was in [*Catalan Countries*](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pa%C3%AFsos_Catalans), and some do speak Catalan and others dont like it. Im not sure, but its complicated.

I remember reading the news, last year, and a member of the Catalan government said something along the lines of when Catalunya becomes its own country, people in Valencia get offered a Catalan passport and that got quite some commotion.

Im going to Valencia this summer, I havent been there yet, so Im really excited! :D</utt><utt uid="0">I think if youve lived there for a few months, the languages will be easier to understand. I dont know how much different Mexican Spanish is from Spanish Spanish, but I dont think it will be too difficult to adapt.

However, I have a Venezuelan friend, and she told me that when she moved to Spain, it seemed like she was in a completely different country, and had to learn Spanish again! 

Thanks! Ill bring out a report, probably on this sub as well, otherwise Ill message you! 

</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">I just saw your post on /r/catalunya  
Wow, theres plenty of stuff here for a 15 day sub</utt><utt uid="1">Hi,

Ill take that as a compliment! ;)

Im trying to post as much relevant information in the subreddit as I can, because I worked on it, take it quite seriously and have a prosperous vision for it. 

Also, now is definitely the testing phase, for example with AutoModerators daily agenda post and sidebar links. Also, I am trying to get (/r/)Tarragona shown up in search results.

I do love Tarragona, so I definitely like working on it as well! :)</utt><utt uid="0">I see youve been busy in here, it looks nice.  
I dont know if I could be of much help but Ill do what I can.</utt><utt uid="1">Moltes gràcies! :-)

If you have some time, I could use some help with translations, especially the [Wiki](https://www.reddit.com/r/Tarragona/wiki/index). :)

Enjoy your Sunday! :D</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Wow, what an amazing photo!</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Now thats a day worth celebrating!</utt><utt uid="1">Ooooh yeah! Do you have any plans to celebrate it? :-)</utt><utt uid="0">Ill probably go find some tapas for dinner, though there isnt anywhere good near where I am at the moment :-/

You?</utt><utt uid="1">Sadly, I had to spend all day studying for an exam! :-(</utt><utt uid="0">Celebrate posumously ;-)</utt><utt uid="1">I passed all of them with pretty good grades, so I am just postponing tapas day... for now! ;)</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog><s><utt uid="0">Aplicació mòbil que té com a finalitat posar en contacte lusuari amb el comerç local.

---

An app that helps you get in touch with local businesses.

---

Aplicación móvil que pretende ponerlo en contacto con locales comerciales.</utt></s></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog><dialog></dialog>